<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "https://thor-f5.er.usgs.gov/ngtoc/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
    <idinfo>
        <citation>
            <citeinfo>
                <origin>U.S. Geological Survey, National Geospatial Technical Operations
                    Center</origin>
                <pubdate>2020</pubdate>
                <title>USGS National Transportation Dataset (NTD) Downloadable Data
                    Collection</title>
                <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
                <pubinfo>
                    <pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
                    <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
                </pubinfo>
                <onlink>https://nationalmap.gov/transport.html</onlink>
            </citeinfo>
        </citation>
        <descript>
            <abstract>The USGS Transportation downloadable data from The National Map (TNM) is based
                on TIGER/Line data provided through U.S. Census Bureau and supplemented with HERE
                road data to create tile cache base maps. Some of the TIGER/Line data includes
                limited corrections done by USGS. Transportation data consists of roads, railroads,
                trails, airports, and other features associated with the transport of people or
                commerce. The data include the name or route designator, classification, and
                location. Transportation data support general mapping and geographic information
                system technology analysis for applications such as traffic safety, congestion
                mitigation, disaster planning, and emergency response. The National Map
                transportation data is commonly combined with other data themes, such as boundaries,
                elevation, hydrography, and structures, to produce general reference base maps. The
                National Map viewer allows free downloads of public domain transportation data in
                either Esri File Geodatabase or Shapefile formats. For additional information on the
                transportation data model, go to https://nationalmap.gov/transport.html.</abstract>
            <purpose>This dataset depicts geographic features on the surface of the earth. It is a
                general purpose dataset for users who are not GIS experts. One intended purpose is
                to support emergency response at all levels of government. The geospatial data are
                from selected National Map data holdings and other government sources.</purpose>
            <supplinf>See https://viewer.nationalmap.gov/help for assistance with The National Map
                viewer, services, or metadata.</supplinf>
        </descript>
        <timeperd>
            <timeinfo>
                <rngdates>
                    <begdate>2014</begdate>
                    <enddate>present</enddate>
                </rngdates>
            </timeinfo>
            <current>publication date</current>
        </timeperd>
        <status>
            <progress>Complete</progress>
            <update>Irregular</update>
        </status>
        <spdom>
            <bounding>
                <westbc>-179.229655487448</westbc>
                <eastbc>179.856674735386</eastbc>
                <northbc>71.4395725901531</northbc>
                <southbc>-14.4246950942767</southbc>
            </bounding>
        </spdom>
        <keywords>
            <theme>
                <themekt>USGS Metadata Identifier</themekt>
                <themekey>USGS:ad3d631d-f51f-4b6a-91a3-e617d6a58b4e</themekey>
            </theme>
            <theme>
                <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
                <themekey>transportation</themekey>
            </theme>
            <theme>
                <themekt>None</themekt>
                <themekey>Roads</themekey>
                <themekey>Airports</themekey>
                <themekey>Airstrips</themekey>
                <themekey>Railways</themekey>
                <themekey>Airport Complex</themekey>
                <themekey>Airport Point</themekey>
                <themekey>Airport Runway</themekey>
                <themekey>Geographic names</themekey>
                <themekey>Juction</themekey>
                <themekey>NavAid</themekey>
                <themekey>TrailFeature</themekey>
                <themekey>Transportation</themekey>
                <themekey>Waterway</themekey>
                <themekey>Trails</themekey>
            </theme>
            <place>
                <placekt>Geographic Names Information System</placekt>
                <placekey>US</placekey>
                <placekey>United States</placekey>
            </place>
        </keywords>
        <accconst>None</accconst>
        <useconst>None. However, users should be aware that temporal changes may have occurred since
            this data set was collected and that some parts of this data may no longer represent
            actual surface conditions. Users should not use this data for critical applications
            without a full awareness of its limitations. Acknowledgment of the U.S. Geological
            Survey would be appreciated for products derived from these data. </useconst>
        <browse>
            <browsen>https://thor-f5.er.usgs.gov/ngtoc/metadata/waf/collections/transportation_thumbnail.jpg</browsen>
            <browsed>Thumbnail JPG image</browsed>
            <browset>JPEG</browset>
        </browse>
        <datacred>USGS TNM - National Transportation Dataset; U.S. Census Bureau - TIGER/Line; HERE
            Road Data</datacred>
    </idinfo>
    <dataqual>
        <attracc>
            <attraccr>Content is derived from USGS national geospatial databases. The data is owned and
                hosted by the USGS, but does not preclude using data sources owned and hosted by other
                organizations, provided that these sources have been approved by the USGS data
                program.</attraccr>
        </attracc>
        <logic>The data was extracted and updated according to standards set by the USGS.</logic>
        <complete>Each layer is extracted from the USGS national geospatial databases.</complete>
        <posacc>
            <horizpa>
                <horizpar>This product is compiled to meet National Map Accuracy Standards (NMAS). NMAS
                    horizontal accuracy requires that at least 90 percent of well-defined points tested are
                    within 0.02 inch of the true position.</horizpar>
            </horizpa>
            <vertacc>
                <vertaccr>Vertical accuracy is not applicable to this dataset.</vertaccr>
            </vertacc>
        </posacc>
        <lineage>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>Oak Ridge National Laboratory</origin>
                        <pubdate>20160402</pubdate>
                        <title>Transportation, Railroads</title>
                        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
                        <othercit>Railroads are derived from an unpublished data set provided to USGS by Oak
                            Ridge National Laboratory (ORNL) Geographic Information Science and Technology Group
                            (GIST). Following is an excerpt from the GIST description of the data set; the
                            original data contain attributes not used by US Topo: The rail lines layer represents
                            the freight lines of the nation's railroad system. The data set covers all 50 states
                            and the District of Columbia, as well as territories and possessions of the United
                            States. No rail lines exist in American Samoa, Guam, Northern Mariana Islands, and the
                            Virgin Islands of the US. Phase 1 of this product is a completed deliverable. This
                            phase involved adding and validating network attribute data including railroad
                            ownership, trackage and haulage rights, operational status, operating subdivisions,
                            signaling systems, track class and traffic density. Phase 2 adjusted the topological
                            alignment of the track using the best available remote sensing imagery. Information
                            originally based on the Department of Transportation (DOT) Federal Railroad
                            Administration (FRA) 1:100K rail network. The data have been updated by Oak Ridge
                            National Laboratory (ORNL) Geographic Information Science and Technology Group
                            (GIST).</othercit>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
                <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <rngdates>
                            <begdate>2014</begdate>
                            <enddate>2014</enddate>
                        </rngdates>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>Railroads - Oak Ridge National Laboratory</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Main track centerlines</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>Federal Aviation Administration</origin>
                        <pubdate>20160402</pubdate>
                        <title>Airports</title>
                        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
                        <othercit>Runway outlines are for Federal Aviation Administration (FAA)-recognized
                            public and private airports in the United States. The FAA runway coordinates,
                            FAA_RunwayID, and Airport Location Codes were used by the USGS to digitize runway
                            outlines on recent NAIP orthoimagery. The digitized data were inspected for accuracy
                            and completeness then loaded into the USGS national transportation
                            database.</othercit>
                        <onlink>http://www.faa.gov</onlink>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
                <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <rngdates>
                            <begdate>2011</begdate>
                            <enddate>2012</enddate>
                        </rngdates>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>Transportation - Airports</srccitea>
                <srccontr>runways</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>Various government agencies and volunteer organizations</origin>
                        <pubdate>20160402</pubdate>
                        <title>Recreational Trails</title>
                        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
                        <othercit>The first recreational trails were added to US Topo maps in 2013. The data for
                            trails come from a variety of sources. Accuracy and currency is the responsibility of
                            the data owner; USGS evaluates the authoritativeness of the source but does not
                            independently verify data accuracy. Trails are not complete, and will not be complete
                            for the foreseeable future. Trails will be added as data become available from land
                            management agencies and other authoritative sources. All recreational trails
                            information presented on US Topo maps is public domain, though the original source
                            data is not necessarily public domain. This metadata section documents all data
                            sources for all maps, not this specific map. Trails listed here are not guaranteed to
                            be present on all relevant maps, due to schedule differences between data delivery and
                            US Topo production schedules. Feature-level metadata is not provided in the US Topo
                            product; there is no link between a line on the map and the source of that specific
                            trail. Notes on data sources follow --------- For the 11 National Scenic Trails (NST):
                            Ice Age National Scenic Trail: data provided by the volunteer organization Ice Age
                            Trail Alliance, http://www.iceagetrail.org, in cooperation with National Park Service
                            and Wisconsin Department of Natural Resources. - Pacific Crest National Scenic Trail:
                            unpublished data provided by US Forest Service - Appalachian National Scenic Trail:
                            data published by the Appalachian Trial Conservancy,
                            http://appalachiantrail.org/about-the-trail/mapping-gis-data, in cooperation with
                            National Park Service - North Country National Scenic Trail: unpublished dataset
                            provided by National Park Service - Arizona National Scenic Trail: data from AZGEO
                            Clearinghouse, https://azgeo.az.gov/azgeo/, in cooperation with U.S. Forest Service -
                            Pacific Northwest National Scenic Trail: unpublished data provided by US Forest
                            Service - Natchez Trace National Scenic Trail: unpublished dataset provided by
                            National Park Service --------- For other trail types and sources: US Fish and
                            Wildlife Service lands: the USFWS Hiking Trails Inventory is administered by the US
                            Department of Transportation Federal Highway Administration, and Pacific Western
                            Technologies, LTD. The purpose of the dataset is to create a baseline inventory of all
                            non-motorized trails on US Fish and Wildlife Service Stations. - US Forest Service
                            lands: trails within National Forests are from unpublished data provided by USFS.
                            These data are developed from sources of differing accuracy. US Topo does not portray
                            access and travel management information indicating which trails are managed for or
                            open to specific modes of travel (motorized/non-motorized) or associated seasons of
                            use. USFS trails (other than selected NSTs described above) are currently shown on US
                            Topo only in Colorado. - The International Mountain Bicycling Association, IMBA,
                            shares their bicycle trails data with USGS as part of an ongoing partnership.
                            IMBA-collected trails are generally not shown inside delineated Federal lands (e.g.,
                            National Forests) on US Topo maps.</othercit>
                        <onlink>http://www.nps.gov/ncrc/programs/nts/nts_trails.html</onlink>
                        <onlink>http://www.pnts.org</onlink>
                        <onlink>http://www.fws.gov/gis/data/national/</onlink>
                        <onlink>https://www.imba.com/</onlink>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
                <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <rngdates>
                            <begdate>2006</begdate>
                            <enddate>2014</enddate>
                        </rngdates>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>Recreational Trails</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Trail centerline</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>U.S. Census Bureau, Geography Division</origin>
                        <pubdate>20160402</pubdate>
                        <title>Transportation, Census Roads</title>
                        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
                        <othercit>Dataset source is Census Bureau MAF/TIGER database extracts in the form of
                            TIGER/Line Shapefiles. The TIGER/Line shapefiles and related database files are an
                            extract of selected geographic and cartographic information from the U.S. Census
                            Bureau's Master Address File/Topologically Integrated Geographic Encoding and
                            Referencing (MAF/TIGER) Database (MTDB). The MTDB represents a seamless national file
                            with no overlaps or gaps between parts, however, each TIGER/Line shapefile is designed
                            to stand alone as an independent dataset, or they can be combined to cover the entire
                            nation. The U.S. Geological Survey filters Census roads to remove short road segments
                            which are less than 500 feet in length, are not named and are classified as local
                            roads. The USGS National Transportation Dataset functional road classification system
                            is applied to the Census datasets. The original TIGER/Line Shapefile products are not
                            copyrighted however TIGER/Line and Census TIGER are registered trademarks of the U.S.
                            Census Bureau. The horizontal spatial accuracy information present in the TIGER/Line
                            shapefiles is provided for the purposes of statistical analysis and census operations
                            only and the data may not be suitable for high-precision measurement applications.
                            Full metadata for TIGER/Line shapefiles is available from U.S. Census
                            Bureau</othercit>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
                <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <rngdates>
                            <begdate>2013</begdate>
                            <enddate>2014</enddate>
                        </rngdates>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>Roads - Census</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Road centerlines, route numbers, road classification, street names</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>Alaska Railroad Corporation</origin>
                        <pubdate>20160402</pubdate>
                        <title>Transportation, Railroads</title>
                        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
                        <othercit>This record applies to Alaska data only. Railroad data is provided by the
                            Alaska Railroad Corporation, and may not include other owner's rail features.
                            Unpublished data provided directly to USGS. Current as of 2012. For more information,
                            contact Alaska Railroad Corporation, 327 W. Ship Creek Ave., Anchorage, AK. 99501,
                            phone 907-265-3100, or emailgrunwaldm@akrrr.com</othercit>
                        <onlink> </onlink>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <srcscale>25000</srcscale>
                <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <rngdates>
                            <begdate>2012</begdate>
                            <enddate>2012</enddate>
                        </rngdates>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>Railroads - Alaska Railroad Corporation</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Main track centerlines</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>Alaska Department of Transportation</origin>
                        <pubdate>20160402</pubdate>
                        <title>Transportation, public domain roads</title>
                        <geoform>Vector digital data</geoform>
                        <othercit>This record applies to Alaska data only. Roads gathered from various state and
                            local sources, integrated by the Alaska Department of Transportation (ADOT) and
                            provided to USGS for use in USGS map products. This specific road dataset is
                            unpublished, but earlier versions are published on the ADOT web site.</othercit>
                        <onlink>http://www.dot.state.ak.us/stwdplng/mapping/</onlink>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <srcscale>25000</srcscale>
                <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <rngdates>
                            <begdate>2013</begdate>
                            <enddate>2013</enddate>
                        </rngdates>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>Roads - Alaska Department of Transportation</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Road centerlines, road classification, street names</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>All geospatial content is taken from national geospatial databases under the
                    stewardship of USGS data programs. The NAIP imagery is provided by a seamless tile service
                    that delivers image data at the resolution and quality of the source imagery. The raster
                    and vector data, including grids and collar information, are processed using ESRI ArcGIS
                    software and exported. Map formatting is performed using a custom application, which
                    includes post-processing to embed the metadata XML document.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20160402</procdate>
            </procstep>
        </lineage>
    </dataqual>    
    <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Vector</direct>
        <ptvctinf>
            <sdtsterm>
                <sdtstype>Void polygon composed of rings</sdtstype>
            </sdtsterm>
            <sdtsterm>
                <sdtstype>Complete chain</sdtstype>
            </sdtsterm>
            <sdtsterm>
                <sdtstype>Complete chain</sdtstype>
                <ptvctcnt>1012</ptvctcnt>
            </sdtsterm>
        </ptvctinf>
    </spdoinfo>
    <spref>
        <horizsys>
            <geograph>
                <latres>0.00001</latres>
                <longres>0.00001</longres>
                <geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
            </geograph>
            <geodetic>
                <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
                <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
                <semiaxis>6378137</semiaxis>
                <denflat>298.2572221</denflat>
            </geodetic>
        </horizsys>
    </spref>
    <eainfo>
        <detailed>
            <enttyp>
                <enttypl>Trans_AirportPoint</enttypl>
                <enttypd>A feature class representing the location of an airport as a single
                    point.</enttypd>
                <enttypds>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</enttypds>
            </enttyp>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <udom>Feature geometry.</udom>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Data_Security</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A code from Executive Order 12958-Classified National Security Information
                    (EO12958) used to describe the highest classification of a United States
                    document (e.g., confidential, secret, top secret, no markings).</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A code from Executive Order 12958-Classified National Security
                            Information (EO12958) used to describe the highest classification of a
                            United States document (e.g., confidential, secret, top secret, no
                            markings).</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Distribution_Policy</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Data access and use constraints.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Data access and use constraints.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>FAA_Airport_Code</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A 3, 4 or 5 character code assigned by the Federal Aviation Administration
                    used to identify the name and location of an airport.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A 3, 4 or 5 character code assigned by the Federal Aviation
                            Administration used to identify the name and location of an
                            airport.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>FCode</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Feature Code. Numeric value that encodes a set of characteristics for a
                    type of feature. This five-digit code has two parts: the first three digits
                    encode the feature type (FType); the last two digits encode values for a unique
                    set of characteristics associated with the feature type. The set of
                    characteristics may be single valued or multi-valued.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Feature Code. Numeric value that encodes a set of characteristics
                            for a type of feature. This five-digit code has two parts: the first
                            three digits encode the feature type (FType); the last two digits encode
                            values for a unique set of characteristics associated with the feature
                            type. The set of characteristics may be single valued or
                            multi-valued.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>FType</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Part of the FCode's numeric value that encodes a set of characteristics for
                    a type of feature. The first three digits encode the feature type (FType); the
                    last two digits encode values for a unique set of characteristics associated
                    with the feature type. The set of characteristics may be single valued or
                    multi-valued.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Part of the FCode's numeric value that encodes a set of
                            characteristics for a type of feature. The first three digits encode the
                            feature type (FType); the last two digits encode values for a unique set
                            of characteristics associated with the feature type. The set of
                            characteristics may be single valued or multi-valued.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>GNIS_ID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A unique, permanent number assigned to a geographic feature in the USGS
                    Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) database. The GNIS contains
                    information about physical and cultural geographic features (excluding roads and
                    highways), including: the Federally recognized name of each feature, a
                    definition of the official feature location (by state, county, USGS topographic
                    map, and geographic coordinates). The number, by design, carries no information
                    or association to the content of the feature record and therefore is not subject
                    to change as attribute values change. Once assigned to a feature, the number is
                    never changed or withdrawn, and never reassigned. The purpose of the number is
                    to uniquely identify that feature as a record in any information system
                    database, dataset, file, or document and for distinguishing it from all other
                    feature records so identified.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A unique, permanent number assigned to a geographic feature in the
                            USGS Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) database. The GNIS
                            contains information about physical and cultural geographic features
                            (excluding roads and highways), including: the Federally recognized name
                            of each feature, a definition of the official feature location (by
                            state, county, USGS topographic map, and geographic coordinates). The
                            number, by design, carries no information or association to the content
                            of the feature record and therefore is not subject to change as
                            attribute values change. Once assigned to a feature, the number is never
                            changed or withdrawn, and never reassigned. The purpose of the number is
                            to uniquely identify that feature as a record in any information system
                            database, dataset, file, or document and for distinguishing it from all
                            other feature records so identified.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LoadDate</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Date and time feature or event was loaded into the database. Timestamp
                    indicating when the feature or event was last edited.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Date and time feature or event was loaded into the database.
                            Timestamp indicating when the feature or event was last
                            edited.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Name</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>The primary official name of an airport complex and the federally
                    recognized name for the airport complex as designated in the Geographic Names
                    Information System (GNIS).</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>The primary official name of an airport complex and the federally
                            recognized name for the airport complex as designated in the Geographic
                            Names Information System (GNIS).</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Permanent_Identifier</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A globally unique and persistent identifier of an entity (for example:
                    feature or event) instance.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A globally unique and persistent identifier of an entity (for
                            example: feature or event) instance.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Source_DataDesc</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Brief narrative of the source dataset.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Brief narrative of the source dataset.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Source_DatasetID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Identifier for the source dataset.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Identifier for the source dataset.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Source_FeatureID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal ID number of the feature or event in the source dataset.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Internal ID number of the feature or event in the source
                            dataset.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Source_Originator</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Name of the organization or individual that developed the source
                    dataset.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Name of the organization or individual that developed the source
                            dataset.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
        </detailed>
        <detailed>
            <enttyp>
                <enttypl>Trans_AirportRunway</enttypl>
                <enttypd>A feature class representing the location of a building or other structure
                    as a single point.</enttypd>
                <enttypds>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</enttypds>
            </enttyp>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <udom>Feature geometry.</udom>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>FAA_Airport_Code</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A 3, 4 or 5 character code assigned by the Federal Aviation Administration
                    used to identify the name and location of an airport.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A 3, 4 or 5 character code assigned by the Federal Aviation
                            Administration used to identify the name and location of an
                            airport.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>FCode</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Feature Code. Numeric value that encodes a set of characteristics for a
                    type of feature. This five-digit code has two parts: the first three digits
                    encode the feature type (FType); the last two digits encode values for a unique
                    set of characteristics associated with the feature type. The set of
                    characteristics may be single valued or multi-valued.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Feature Code. Numeric value that encodes a set of characteristics
                            for a type of feature. This five-digit code has two parts: the first
                            three digits encode the feature type (FType); the last two digits encode
                            values for a unique set of characteristics associated with the feature
                            type. The set of characteristics may be single valued or
                            multi-valued.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>GNIS_ID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A unique, permanent number assigned to a geographic feature in the USGS
                    Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) database. The GNIS contains
                    information about physical and cultural geographic features (excluding roads and
                    highways), including: the Federally recognized name of each feature, a
                    definition of the official feature location (by state, county, USGS topographic
                    map, and geographic coordinates). The number, by design, carries no information
                    or association to the content of the feature record and therefore is not subject
                    to change as attribute values change. Once assigned to a feature, the number is
                    never changed or withdrawn, and never reassigned. The purpose of the number is
                    to uniquely identify that feature as a record in any information system
                    database, dataset, file, or document and for distinguishing it from all other
                    feature records so identified.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A unique, permanent number assigned to a geographic feature in the
                            USGS Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) database. The GNIS
                            contains information about physical and cultural geographic features
                            (excluding roads and highways), including: the Federally recognized name
                            of each feature, a definition of the official feature location (by
                            state, county, USGS topographic map, and geographic coordinates). The
                            number, by design, carries no information or association to the content
                            of the feature record and therefore is not subject to change as
                            attribute values change. Once assigned to a feature, the number is never
                            changed or withdrawn, and never reassigned. The purpose of the number is
                            to uniquely identify that feature as a record in any information system
                            database, dataset, file, or document and for distinguishing it from all
                            other feature records so identified.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LoadDate</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Date and time feature or event was loaded into the database. Timestamp
                    indicating when the feature or event was last edited.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Date and time feature or event was loaded into the database.
                            Timestamp indicating when the feature or event was last
                            edited.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Name</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>The primary official name of an airport complex and the federally
                    recognized name for the airport complex as designated in the Geographic Names
                    Information System (GNIS).</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>The primary official name of an airport complex and the federally
                            recognized name for the airport complex as designated in the Geographic
                            Names Information System (GNIS).</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Permanent_Identifier</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A globally unique and persistent identifier of an entity (for example:
                    feature or event) instance.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A globally unique and persistent identifier of an entity (for
                            example: feature or event) instance.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Runway_Length</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Length in feet of an airport runway.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Personal communication from Scott McDougal, USGS-NGTOC Transportation
                    Subject Matter Expert, 2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Length in feet of an airport runway.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>Personal communication from Scott McDougal, USGS-NGTOC
                            Transportation Subject Matter Expert, 2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Runway_Status</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Active Status of an airport runway</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Personal communication from Scott McDougal, USGS-NGTOC Transportation
                    Subject Matter Expert, 2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Active Status of an airport runway</codesetn>
                        <codesets>Communication from Scott McDougal, USGS-NGTOC Transportation
                            Subject Matter Expert, 2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Runway_Width</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Width in feet of an airport runway.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Personal communication from Scott McDougal, USGS-NGTOC Transportation
                    Subject Matter Expert, 2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Width in feet of an airport runway.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>Personal communication from Scott McDougal, USGS-NGTOC
                            Transportation Subject Matter Expert, 2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Length of the feature, which may differ from the field measured length due
                    to differences in calculation. Units are map units.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Length of the feature, which may differ from the field measured
                            length due to differences in calculation. Units are map
                            units.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape_Area</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Area of feature in map units squared.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Area of feature in map units squared.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape_Length</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Length of the feature, which may differ from the field measured length due
                    to differences in calculation. Units are map units.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Length of the feature, which may differ from the field measured
                            length due to differences in calculation. Units are map
                            units.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Source_DataDesc</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Brief narrative of the source dataset.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Brief narrative of the source dataset.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Source_DatasetID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Identifier for the source dataset.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Identifier for the source dataset.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Source_FeatureID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal ID number of the feature or event in the source dataset.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Internal ID number of the feature or event in the source
                            dataset.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Source_Originator</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Name of the organization or individual that developed the source
                    dataset.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Name of the organization or individual that developed the source
                            dataset.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>State_Route</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A numeric identifier designating the road segments that form a particular
                    path through the transportation system, as attributed by a state-level
                    transportation organization.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A numeric identifier designating the road segments that form a
                            particular path through the transportation system, as attributed by a
                            state-level transportation organization.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Surface_Material</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A description of of a transportation component's surface.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A description of of a transportation component's
                            surface.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Width</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Width of the trail segment in meters. Dimension of feature taken
                    perpendicular to its primary alignment of use and generally in the horizontal
                    plane.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Width of the trail segment in meters. Dimension of feature taken
                            perpendicular to its primary alignment of use and generally in the
                            horizontal plane.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
        </detailed>
        <detailed>
            <enttyp>
                <enttypl>Trans_RailFeature</enttypl>
                <enttypd>A feature class representing the location of a building or other structure
                    as a single point.</enttypd>
                <enttypds>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</enttypds>
            </enttyp>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <udom>Feature geometry.</udom>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Data_Security</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A code from Executive Order 12958-Classified National Security Information
                    (EO12958) used to describe the highest classification of a United States
                    document (e.g., confidential, secret, top secret, no markings).</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A code from Executive Order 12958-Classified National Security
                            Information (EO12958) used to describe the highest classification of a
                            United States document (e.g., confidential, secret, top secret, no
                            markings).</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Distribution_Policy</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Data access and use constraints.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Data access and use constraints.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>FCode</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Feature Code. Numeric value that encodes a set of characteristics for a
                    type of feature. This five-digit code has two parts: the first three digits
                    encode the feature type (FType); the last two digits encode values for a unique
                    set of characteristics associated with the feature type. The set of
                    characteristics may be single valued or multi-valued.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Feature Code. Numeric value that encodes a set of characteristics
                            for a type of feature. This five-digit code has two parts: the first
                            three digits encode the feature type (FType); the last two digits encode
                            values for a unique set of characteristics associated with the feature
                            type. The set of characteristics may be single valued or
                            multi-valued.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>GNIS_ID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A unique, permanent number assigned to a geographic feature in the USGS
                    Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) database. The GNIS contains
                    information about physical and cultural geographic features (excluding roads and
                    highways), including: the Federally recognized name of each feature, a
                    definition of the official feature location (by state, county, USGS topographic
                    map, and geographic coordinates). The number, by design, carries no information
                    or association to the content of the feature record and therefore is not subject
                    to change as attribute values change. Once assigned to a feature, the number is
                    never changed or withdrawn, and never reassigned. The purpose of the number is
                    to uniquely identify that feature as a record in any information system
                    database, dataset, file, or document and for distinguishing it from all other
                    feature records so identified.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A unique, permanent number assigned to a geographic feature in the
                            USGS Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) database. The GNIS
                            contains information about physical and cultural geographic features
                            (excluding roads and highways), including: the Federally recognized name
                            of each feature, a definition of the official feature location (by
                            state, county, USGS topographic map, and geographic coordinates). The
                            number, by design, carries no information or association to the content
                            of the feature record and therefore is not subject to change as
                            attribute values change. Once assigned to a feature, the number is never
                            changed or withdrawn, and never reassigned. The purpose of the number is
                            to uniquely identify that feature as a record in any information system
                            database, dataset, file, or document and for distinguishing it from all
                            other feature records so identified.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LengthKM</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Length of the rail segment in kilometers (km).</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Length of the rail segment in kilometers (km).</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LoadDate</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Date and time feature or event was loaded into the database. Timestamp
                    indicating when the feature or event was last edited.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Date and time feature or event was loaded into the database.
                            Timestamp indicating when the feature or event was last
                            edited.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Name</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>The primary official name of an airport complex and the federally
                    recognized name for the airport complex as designated in the Geographic Names
                    Information System (GNIS).</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>The primary official name of an airport complex and the federally
                            recognized name for the airport complex as designated in the Geographic
                            Names Information System (GNIS).</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Owner</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>The person(s) or organization(s) that possess the rail line.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>The person(s) or organization(s) that possess the rail
                            line.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Permanent_Identifier</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A globally unique and persistent identifier of an entity (for example:
                    feature or event) instance.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A globally unique and persistent identifier of an entity (for
                            example: feature or event) instance.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Rail_Class</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A classification describing the area served by the rail feature.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A classification describing the area served by the rail
                            feature.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Rail_Usage</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>The use(s) to which a railway is put as part of a transportation
                    system.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>The use(s) to which a railway is put as part of a transportation
                            system.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Length of the feature, which may differ from the field measured length due
                    to differences in calculation. Units are map units.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Length of the feature, which may differ from the field measured
                            length due to differences in calculation. Units are map
                            units.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape_Length</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Length of the feature, which may differ from the field measured length due
                    to differences in calculation. Units are map units.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Length of the feature, which may differ from the field measured
                            length due to differences in calculation. Units are map
                            units.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Source_DataDesc</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Brief narrative of the source dataset.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Brief narrative of the source dataset.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Source_DatasetID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Identifier for the source dataset.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Identifier for the source dataset.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Source_FeatureID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal ID number of the feature or event in the source dataset.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Internal ID number of the feature or event in the source
                            dataset.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Source_Originator</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Name of the organization or individual that developed the source
                    dataset.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Name of the organization or individual that developed the source
                            dataset.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
        </detailed>
        <detailed>
            <enttyp>
                <enttypl>Trans_RoadSegment</enttypl>
                <enttypd>A feature class representing the location of a building or other structure
                    as a single point.</enttypd>
                <enttypds>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</enttypds>
            </enttyp>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <udom>Feature geometry.</udom>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>County_Route</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A numeric identifier designating the road segments that form a particular
                    path through the transportation system, as attributed by a state or county-level
                    transportation organization.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A numeric identifier designating the road segments that form a
                            particular path through the transportation system, as attributed by a
                            state or county-level transportation organization.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Data_Security</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A code from Executive Order 12958-Classified National Security Information
                    (EO12958) used to describe the highest classification of a United States
                    document (e.g., confidential, secret, top secret, no markings).</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A code from Executive Order 12958-Classified National Security
                            Information (EO12958) used to describe the highest classification of a
                            United States document (e.g., confidential, secret, top secret, no
                            markings).</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Distribution_Policy</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Data access and use constraints.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Data access and use constraints.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Full_Street_Name</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Official name of a street as assigned by a local governing authority, or an
                    alternate (alias) name that is used and recognized. The full street name is the
                    combination of the following data types: [Prefix_Dir] + [Prefix_Type] +
                    [Base_Street_Name] + [Street_Type] + [Suffix_Dir] + [Suffix_Type]. For example,
                    North Broadway Avenue or North Avenue A.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Official name of a street as assigned by a local governing
                            authority, or an alternate (alias) name that is used and recognized. The
                            full street name is the combination of the following data types:
                            [Prefix_Dir] + [Prefix_Type] + [Base_Street_Name] + [Street_Type] +
                            [Suffix_Dir] + [Suffix_Type]. For example, North Broadway Avenue or
                            North Avenue A.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>GNIS_ID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A unique, permanent number assigned to a geographic feature in the USGS
                    Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) database. The GNIS contains
                    information about physical and cultural geographic features (excluding roads and
                    highways), including: the Federally recognized name of each feature, a
                    definition of the official feature location (by state, county, USGS topographic
                    map, and geographic coordinates). The number, by design, carries no information
                    or association to the content of the feature record and therefore is not subject
                    to change as attribute values change. Once assigned to a feature, the number is
                    never changed or withdrawn, and never reassigned. The purpose of the number is
                    to uniquely identify that feature as a record in any information system
                    database, dataset, file, or document and for distinguishing it from all other
                    feature records so identified.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A unique, permanent number assigned to a geographic feature in the
                            USGS Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) database. The GNIS
                            contains information about physical and cultural geographic features
                            (excluding roads and highways), including: the Federally recognized name
                            of each feature, a definition of the official feature location (by
                            state, county, USGS topographic map, and geographic coordinates). The
                            number, by design, carries no information or association to the content
                            of the feature record and therefore is not subject to change as
                            attribute values change. Once assigned to a feature, the number is never
                            changed or withdrawn, and never reassigned. The purpose of the number is
                            to uniquely identify that feature as a record in any information system
                            database, dataset, file, or document and for distinguishing it from all
                            other feature records so identified.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>High_Address_Left</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>The house number that is the low end of the range of addresses on the left
                    side of the segment.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>The house number that is the low end of the range of addresses on
                            the left side of the segment.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>High_Address_Right</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>The house number that is the low end of the range of addresses on the left
                    side of the segment.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>The house number that is the low end of the range of addresses on
                            the left side of the segment.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Interstate</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A numeric or alphanumeric identifier designating the road segments that
                    form a particular path through the transportation system, as attributed by the
                    US Department of Transportation. It includes the Interstate number and Business,
                    Bypass, Alternate, or Scenic designation.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A numeric or alphanumeric identifier designating the road segments
                            that form a particular path through the transportation system, as
                            attributed by the US Department of Transportation. It includes the
                            Interstate number and Business, Bypass, Alternate, or Scenic
                            designation.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>IsOneWay</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Indication that a road is intended to be used only in a single
                    direction.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Indication that a road is intended to be used only in a single
                            direction.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LoadDate</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Date and time feature or event was loaded into the database. Timestamp
                    indicating when the feature or event was last edited.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Date and time feature or event was loaded into the database.
                            Timestamp indicating when the feature or event was last
                            edited.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Low_Address_Left</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>The house number that is the low end of the range of addresses on the left
                    side of the segment.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>The house number that is the low end of the range of addresses on
                            the left side of the segment.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Low_Address_Right</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>The house number that is the low end of the range of addresses on the right
                    side of the segment.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>The house number that is the low end of the range of addresses on
                            the right side of the segment.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>OneWay_Direction</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Cardinal or ordinal direction of traffic flow on a one way road.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Cardinal or ordinal direction of traffic flow on a one way
                            road.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Permanent_Identifier</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A globally unique and persistent identifier of an entity (for example:
                    feature or event) instance.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A globally unique and persistent identifier of an entity (for
                            example: feature or event) instance.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Rail_Class</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A classification describing the area served by the rail feature.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A classification describing the area served by the rail
                            feature.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Road_Class</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>The category of roads based on design, weatherability, their governmental
                    designation, the character of service that they provide, and the importance of
                    the role that the road or ferry connection performs in the connectivity of the
                    total road network.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>The category of roads based on design, weatherability, their
                            governmental designation, the character of service that they provide,
                            and the importance of the role that the road or ferry connection
                            performs in the connectivity of the total road network.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Length of the feature, which may differ from the field measured length due
                    to differences in calculation. Units are map units.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Length of the feature, which may differ from the field measured
                            length due to differences in calculation. Units are map
                            units.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape_Area</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Area of feature in map units squared.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Area of feature in map units squared.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape_Length</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Length of the feature, which may differ from the field measured length due
                    to differences in calculation. Units are map units.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Length of the feature, which may differ from the field measured
                            length due to differences in calculation. Units are map
                            units.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Source_DataDesc</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Brief narrative of the source dataset.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Brief narrative of the source dataset.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Source_DatasetID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Identifier for the source dataset.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Identifier for the source dataset.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Source_FeatureID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal ID number of the feature or event in the source dataset.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Internal ID number of the feature or event in the source
                            dataset.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Source_Originator</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Name of the organization or individual that developed the source
                    dataset.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Name of the organization or individual that developed the source
                            dataset.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>State_Route</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A numeric identifier designating the road segments that form a particular
                    path through the transportation system, as attributed by a state-level
                    transportation organization.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A numeric identifier designating the road segments that form a
                            particular path through the transportation system, as attributed by a
                            state-level transportation organization.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>StCo_FIPSCode</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A five-digit Federal Information Processing Standard (FIPS) numeric code
                    that uniquely identifies counties and equivalent entities in the United States,
                    Its possessions, and Associated states. The first two digits are the numeric
                    code for a US State (FIPS PUB 5-2) and the last three digits are the numeric
                    code for a county (FIPS PUB 6-4) within the state or possession.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A five-digit Federal Information Processing Standard (FIPS)
                            numeric code that uniquely identifies counties and equivalent entities
                            in the United States, Its possessions, and Associated states. The first
                            two digits are the numeric code for a US State (FIPS PUB 5-2) and the
                            last three digits are the numeric code for a county (FIPS PUB 6-4)
                            within the state or possession.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>US_Route</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A numeric or alphanumeric identifier designating the road segments that
                    form a particular path through the transportation system, as attributed by the
                    US Department of Transportation. It includes the US highway number and Business,
                    Bypass, Alternate, or Scenic designation.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A numeric or alphanumeric identifier designating the road segments
                            that form a particular path through the transportation system, as
                            attributed by the US Department of Transportation. It includes the US
                            highway number and Business, Bypass, Alternate, or Scenic
                            designation.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Width</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Width of the trail segment in meters. Dimension of feature taken
                    perpendicular to its primary alignment of use and generally in the horizontal
                    plane.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Width of the trail segment in meters. Dimension of feature taken
                            perpendicular to its primary alignment of use and generally in the
                            horizontal plane.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Zip_Left</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>ZIP code associated with the most inclusive address range on the left side
                    of the segment.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>ZIP code associated with the most inclusive address range on the
                            left side of the segment.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Zip_Right</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>ZIP code associated with the most inclusive address range on the right side
                    of the segment.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>ZIP code associated with the most inclusive address range on the
                            right side of the segment.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
        </detailed>
        <detailed>
            <enttyp>
                <enttypl>Trans_TrailSegment</enttypl>
                <enttypd>A feature class representing the location of a building or other structure
                    as a single point.</enttypd>
                <enttypds>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</enttypds>
            </enttyp>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <udom>Feature geometry.</udom>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>ATV</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Indicator of whether or not all-terrain vehicles (ATVs) are allowed on the
                    trail.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Indicator of whether or not all-terrain vehicles (ATVs) are
                            allowed on the trail.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Bike</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Indicator of whether or not bicycles are allowed on the trail.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Indicator of whether or not bicycles are allowed on the
                            trail.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Data_Security</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A code from Executive Order 12958-Classified National Security Information
                    (EO12958) used to describe the highest classification of a United States
                    document (e.g., confidential, secret, top secret, no markings).</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A code from Executive Order 12958-Classified National Security
                            Information (EO12958) used to describe the highest classification of a
                            United States document (e.g., confidential, secret, top secret, no
                            markings).</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Distribution_Policy</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Data access and use constraints.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Data access and use constraints.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>GNIS_ID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A unique, permanent number assigned to a geographic feature in the USGS
                    Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) database. The GNIS contains
                    information about physical and cultural geographic features (excluding roads and
                    highways), including: the Federally recognized name of each feature, a
                    definition of the official feature location (by state, county, USGS topographic
                    map, and geographic coordinates). The number, by design, carries no information
                    or association to the content of the feature record and therefore is not subject
                    to change as attribute values change. Once assigned to a feature, the number is
                    never changed or withdrawn, and never reassigned. The purpose of the number is
                    to uniquely identify that feature as a record in any information system
                    database, dataset, file, or document and for distinguishing it from all other
                    feature records so identified.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A unique, permanent number assigned to a geographic feature in the
                            USGS Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) database. The GNIS
                            contains information about physical and cultural geographic features
                            (excluding roads and highways), including: the Federally recognized name
                            of each feature, a definition of the official feature location (by
                            state, county, USGS topographic map, and geographic coordinates). The
                            number, by design, carries no information or association to the content
                            of the feature record and therefore is not subject to change as
                            attribute values change. Once assigned to a feature, the number is never
                            changed or withdrawn, and never reassigned. The purpose of the number is
                            to uniquely identify that feature as a record in any information system
                            database, dataset, file, or document and for distinguishing it from all
                            other feature records so identified.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Hike</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Indicator of whether or not pedestrians are allowed on the trail.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Indicator of whether or not pedestrians are allowed on the
                            trail.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Length</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Length of the trail segment in meters. Dimension of feature taken along its
                    primary alignment of use and generally in the horizontal plane.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Length of the trail segment in meters. Dimension of feature taken
                            along its primary alignment of use and generally in the horizontal
                            plane.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LoadDate</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Date and time feature or event was loaded into the database. Timestamp
                    indicating when the feature or event was last edited.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Date and time feature or event was loaded into the database.
                            Timestamp indicating when the feature or event was last
                            edited.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Motorcycle</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>The house number that is the low end of the range of addresses on the right
                    side of the segment.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>The house number that is the low end of the range of addresses on
                            the right side of the segment.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Name</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>The primary official name of an airport complex and the federally
                    recognized name for the airport complex as designated in the Geographic Names
                    Information System (GNIS).</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>The primary official name of an airport complex and the federally
                            recognized name for the airport complex as designated in the Geographic
                            Names Information System (GNIS).</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>NonMotorizedOnly</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Indicator of whether or not motorized vehicles are allowed on the
                    trail.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Indicator of whether or not motorized vehicles are allowed on the
                            trail.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>PackOrSaddle</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Indicator of whether or not horses with pack saddles carrying loads or with
                    saddles carrying people are allowed on the trail.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Indicator of whether or not horses with pack saddles carrying
                            loads or with saddles carrying people are allowed on the
                            trail.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Permanent_Identifier</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A globally unique and persistent identifier of an entity (for example:
                    feature or event) instance.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>A globally unique and persistent identifier of an entity (for
                            example: feature or event) instance.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Length of the feature, which may differ from the field measured length due
                    to differences in calculation. Units are map units.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Length of the feature, which may differ from the field measured
                            length due to differences in calculation. Units are map
                            units.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Source_DataDesc</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Brief narrative of the source dataset.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Brief narrative of the source dataset.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Source_DatasetID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Identifier for the source dataset.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Identifier for the source dataset.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Source_FeatureID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal ID number of the feature or event in the source dataset.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Internal ID number of the feature or event in the source
                            dataset.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Source_Originator</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Name of the organization or individual that developed the source
                    dataset.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Name of the organization or individual that developed the source
                            dataset.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Width</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Width of the trail segment in meters. Dimension of feature taken
                    perpendicular to its primary alignment of use and generally in the horizontal
                    plane.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                    2013</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <codesetd>
                        <codesetn>Width of the trail segment in meters. Dimension of feature taken
                            perpendicular to its primary alignment of use and generally in the
                            horizontal plane.</codesetn>
                        <codesets>USGS NGTOC archives' Data Dictionary: Trans_v11.xls, draft copy
                            2013</codesets>
                    </codesetd>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
        </detailed>
    </eainfo>
    <distinfo>
        <distrib>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey, National Geospatial Technical Operations
                        Center</cntorg>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>1400 Independence Road</address>
                    <city>Rolla</city>
                    <state>MO</state>
                    <postal>65401</postal>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>Box 25046 Denver Federal Center</address>
                    <city>Lakewood</city>
                    <state>CO</state>
                    <postal>80225</postal>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>1-888-275-8747</cntvoice>
                <cntemail>tnm_help@usgs.gov</cntemail>
                <hours>Monday through Friday 8:00 AM to 4:00 PM Eastern Time Zone USA</hours>
                <cntinst>Please visit http://www.usgs.gov/ask/, call 1-888-ASK-USGS or email tnm_help@usgs.gov to contact us.</cntinst>
            </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
        <distliab>No liability for content or accuracy is presumed by USGS for data.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
            <digform>
                <digtinfo>
                    <formname>WAF</formname>
                    <formcont>Web Accessible Folder</formcont>
                </digtinfo>
                <digtopt>
                    <onlinopt>
                        <computer>
                            <networka>
                                <networkr>https://thor-f5.er.usgs.gov/ngtoc/metadata/waf/transportation/ntd/</networkr>
                            </networka>
                        </computer>
                    </onlinopt>
                </digtopt>
            </digform>
            <fees>None.</fees>
        </stdorder>
        <stdorder>
            <digform>
                <digtinfo>
                    <formname>FileGDB</formname>
                    <formcont>ESRI File Geodatabase</formcont>
                </digtinfo>
                <digtopt>
                    <onlinopt>
                        <computer>
                            <networka>
                                <networkr>https://prd-tnm.s3.amazonaws.com/index.html?prefix=StagedProducts/Tran/GDB/</networkr>
                            </networka>
                        </computer>
                    </onlinopt>
                </digtopt>
            </digform>
            <fees>None.</fees>
        </stdorder>
        <stdorder>
            <digform>
                <digtinfo>
                    <formname>Shapefile</formname>
                    <formcont>ESRI Shapefile</formcont>
                </digtinfo>
                <digtopt>
                    <onlinopt>
                        <computer>
                            <networka>
                                <networkr>https://prd-tnm.s3.amazonaws.com/index.html?prefix=StagedProducts/Tran/Shape/</networkr>
                            </networka>
                        </computer>
                    </onlinopt>
                </digtopt>
            </digform>
            <fees>None.</fees>
        </stdorder>
        <stdorder>
            <digform>
                <digtinfo>
                    <formname>USGS Transportation Map Server (ArcGIS)</formname>
                    <formvern>10.71</formvern>
                    <formspec>http://www.geoplatform.gov/spec/esri-map-rest</formspec>
                    <formcont>An ArcGIS Map Service for visualizing GNIS features.</formcont>
                </digtinfo>
                <digtopt>
                    <onlinopt>
                        <computer>
                            <networka>
                                <networkr>https://carto.nationalmap.gov/arcgis/rest/services/transportation/MapServer</networkr>
                            </networka>
                        </computer>
                    </onlinopt>
                </digtopt>
            </digform>
            <digform>
                <digtinfo>
                    <formname>USGS Transportation Map Server (OGC WMS)</formname>
                    <formvern>1.3.0</formvern>
                    <formspec>http://opengis.net/spec/wms</formspec>
                    <formcont>An OGC WMS Map Service for visualizing transportation features.</formcont>
                </digtinfo>
                <digtopt>
                    <onlinopt>
                        <computer>
                            <networka>
                                <networkr>https://carto.nationalmap.gov/arcgis/services/transportation/MapServer/WMSServer?request=GetCapabilities&amp;service=WMS</networkr>
                            </networka>
                        </computer>
                    </onlinopt>
                </digtopt>
            </digform>
            <digform>
                <digtinfo>
                    <formname>USGS Transportation Feature Server (OGC WFS)</formname>
                    <formvern>2.0</formvern>
                    <formspec>http://opengis.net/spec/wfs</formspec>
                    <formcont>An OGC WFS Service for accessing transportation features.</formcont>
                </digtinfo>
                <digtopt>
                    <onlinopt>
                        <computer>
                            <networka>
                                <networkr>https://carto-wfs.nationalmap.gov/arcgis/services/transportation/MapServer/WFSServer?request=GetCapabilities&amp;service=WFS</networkr>
                            </networka>
                        </computer>
                    </onlinopt>
                </digtopt>
            </digform>
            <fees>NONE</fees>
        </stdorder>        
    </distinfo>
    <metainfo>
        <metd>20201113</metd>
        <metc>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey, National Geospatial Technical Operations
                        Center</cntorg>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>1400 Independence Road</address>
                    <city>Rolla</city>
                    <state>MO</state>
                    <postal>65401</postal>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>Box 25046 Denver Federal Center</address>
                    <city>Lakewood</city>
                    <state>CO</state>
                    <postal>80225</postal>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>1-888-275-8747</cntvoice>
                <cntemail>tnm_help@usgs.gov</cntemail>
                <hours>Monday through Friday 8:00 AM to 4:00 PM Eastern Time Zone USA</hours>
                <cntinst>Please visit http://www.usgs.gov/ask/, call 1-888-ASK-USGS or email tnm_help@usgs.gov to contact us.</cntinst>
            </cntinfo>
        </metc>
        <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
        <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
