<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata><Esri><PublishedDocID>{54A8FEC4-97C2-40D1-90FE-DA932E6B5EFE}</PublishedDocID></Esri><idinfo><keywords><theme><themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt><themekey>environment</themekey></theme><theme><themekt>EPA GIS Keyword Thesaurus</themekt><themekey>Ecosystem</themekey><themekey>Environment</themekey></theme><theme><themekt>EnviroAtlas</themekt><themekey>12-digit HUCs</themekey><themekey>Biodiversity</themekey><themekey>Biology</themekey><themekey>Biota</themekey><themekey>Ecosystem Services</themekey><themekey>EnviroAtlas</themekey><themekey>Environment</themekey><themekey>Environmental Atlas</themekey><themekey>Habitat</themekey><themekey>Recreation</themekey><themekey>Supply of Ecosystem Services</themekey><themekey>Species</themekey></theme><place><placekt>None</placekt><placekey>Alabama</placekey><placekey>Arizona</placekey><placekey>Arkansas</placekey><placekey>California</placekey><placekey>Colorado</placekey><placekey>Connecticut</placekey><placekey>Delaware</placekey><placekey>Florida</placekey><placekey>Georgia</placekey><placekey>Idaho</placekey><placekey>Illinois</placekey><placekey>Indiana</placekey><placekey>Iowa</placekey><placekey>Kansas</placekey><placekey>Kentucky</placekey><placekey>Louisiana</placekey><placekey>Maine</placekey><placekey>Maryland</placekey><placekey>Massachusetts</placekey><placekey>Michigan</placekey><placekey>Minnesota</placekey><placekey>Mississippi</placekey><placekey>Missouri</placekey><placekey>Montana</placekey><placekey>Nebraska</placekey><placekey>Nevada</placekey><placekey>New Hampshire</placekey><placekey>New Jersey</placekey><placekey>New Mexico</placekey><placekey>New York</placekey><placekey>North Carolina</placekey><placekey>North Dakota</placekey><placekey>Ohio</placekey><placekey>Oklahoma</placekey><placekey>Oregon</placekey><placekey>Pennsylvania</placekey><placekey>Rhode Island</placekey><placekey>South Carolina</placekey><placekey>South Dakota</placekey><placekey>Tennessee</placekey><placekey>Texas</placekey><placekey>United States</placekey><placekey>Utah</placekey><placekey>Vermont</placekey><placekey>Virginia</placekey><placekey>Washington</placekey><placekey>Washington DC</placekey><placekey>West Virginia</placekey><placekey>Wisconsin</placekey><placekey>Wyoming</placekey></place></keywords><citation><citeinfo><origin>Center for Applied Spatial Ecology, NMCFWRU, NMSU</origin><title>EnviroAtlas - Total reptile species by 12-digit HUC for the conterminous United States</title><pubinfo><publish>U.S. EPA Office of Research &amp; Development (ORD) - National Exposure Research Laboratory (NERL)</publish><pubplace>Research Triangle Park, NC</pubplace></pubinfo><pubdate>2012</pubdate><onlink>https://edg.epa.gov/data/Public/ORD/EnviroAtlas/National</onlink><onlink>https://enviroatlas.epa.gov/arcgis/rest/services/National/National2016_master/MapServer</onlink><onlink>https://www.epa.gov/enviroatlas/enviroatlas-data</onlink><onlink>https://www.epa.gov/enviroatlas</onlink></citeinfo></citation><timeperd><current>Publication date</current><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>20130325</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>As needed</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>-128.02839229</westbc><eastbc>-65.20336449</eastbc><northbc>51.6773602</northbc><southbc>22.7348894</southbc></bounding></spdom><accconst>None.</accconst><useconst>None. Please check sources, scale, accuracy, currentness and other available information. Please confirm that you are using the most recent copy of both data and metadata.  Acknowledgement of the EPA would be appreciated.</useconst><descript><abstract>This EnviroAtlas dataset was produced by a joint effort of New Mexico State University, US Environmental Protection Agency (US EPA,) and the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) to support research and online mapping activities related to EnviroAtlas. Ecosystem services, i.e., services provided to humans from ecological systems have become a key issue of this century in resource management, conservation planning, and environmental decision analysis.  Mapping and quantifying ecosystem services have become strategic national interests for integrating ecology with economics to help understand the effects of human policies and actions and their subsequent impacts on both ecosystem function and human well-being. Some aspects of biodiversity are valued by humans in varied ways, and thus are important to include in any assessment that seeks to identify and quantify the benefits of ecosystems to humans. Some biodiversity metrics clearly reflect ecosystem services (e.g., abundance and diversity of harvestable species), whereas others may reflect indirect and difficult to quantify relationships to services (e.g., relevance of species diversity to ecosystem resilience, cultural and aesthetic values). Wildlife habitat has been modeled at broad spatial scales and can be used to map a number of biodiversity metrics. We map 15 biodiversity metrics reflecting ecosystem services or other aspects of biodiversity for all vertebrate species except fish. Metrics include species richness for all vertebrates, specific taxon groups, harvestable species (i.e., upland game, waterfowl, furbearers, small game, and big game), threatened and endangered species, and state-designated species of greatest conservation need, and also a metric for ecosystem (i.e., land cover) diversity. This dataset contains information on Reptile Species Richness, the number of reptile species per 12-digit Hydrologic Unit (HUC). The EnviroAtlas (https://www.epa.gov/enviroatlas) allows the user to interact with a web-based, easy-to-use, mapping application to view and analyze multiple ecosystem services for the contiguous United States. The dataset is available as downloadable data (https://edg.epa.gov/data/Public/ORD/EnviroAtlas) or as an EnviroAtlas map service. Additional descriptive information about each attribute in this dataset can be found in its associated EnviroAtlas Fact Sheet (https://www.epa.gov/enviroatlas/enviroatlas-fact-sheets).
			</abstract><purpose>The biodiversity metrics were created from range maps created by the USGS Gap Analysis Program.  This data could be used in conjunction with other biodiversity data or ecosystem service data to identify concordance and discordance between metrics. Areas of concordance highlight the similarity between the two metrics.  Areas of discordance highlight dissimilar areas, but must then be reviewed to understand why the dissimilarity occurs.  The overall goal of EnviroAtlas is to employ and develop the best available science to map indicators of ecosystem services production, demand, and drivers for the nation.

Reptile Species Richness provides a characterization of the area of interest.  Certain reptiles (e.g. snakes) can play an important part in maintaining rodent populations.  Other reptiles can be an important prey item for large animals. This metric is important to ecological service categories related to biodiversity conservation and recreation, culture, and aesthetics.</purpose></descript><secinfo><secsys>FIPS Pub 199</secsys><secclass>public</secclass><sechandl>Standard Technical Controls</sechandl></secinfo><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>US Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park</cntorg><cntper>EnviroAtlas Coordinator</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>ORD/NERL/EnviroAtlas</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>109 TW Alexander Dr.</address><city>Research Triangle Park</city><state>NC</state><postal>27711</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>000-000-0000</cntvoice><cntemail>EnviroAtlas@epa.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></ptcontac></idinfo><dataqual><logic>Tests for integrity have not been performed.</logic><complete>Features represented have not been tested for completeness</complete><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>Data were collected using methods that have unknown accuracy (EPA National Geospatial Data Policy [NGDP] Accuracy Tier 10). For more information, please see EPA's NGDP at https://www.epa.gov/geospatial/geospatial-policies-and-standards</horizpar></horizpa></posacc><lineage><procstep><procdate>04012013</procdate><procdesc>Individual species ranges for the USGS's gap analysis data were created using literature</procdesc></procstep><procstep><procdate>04012013</procdate><procdesc>Total number of reptile species from the gap analysis data summed for each 12-digit HUC </procdesc></procstep></lineage></dataqual><spref><horizsys><planar><planci><plance>coordinate pair</plance><plandu>meters</plandu><coordrep><absres>0.000001</absres><ordres>0.000001</ordres></coordrep></planci><mapproj><mapprojn>Albers Conical Equal Area</mapprojn><albers><stdparll>29.500000</stdparll><stdparll>45.500000</stdparll><longcm>-96.000000</longcm><latprjo>23.000000</latprjo><feast>0.000000</feast><fnorth>0.000000</fnorth></albers></mapproj></planar><geodetic><horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn><ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips><semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis><denflat>298.257222</denflat></geodetic></horizsys></spref><distinfo><resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc><distliab>https://edg.epa.gov/EPA_Data_License.htm</distliab><distrib><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>US Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park</cntorg><cntper>EnviroAtlas Coordinator</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>ORD/NERL/EnviroAtlas</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>109 TW Alexander Dr.</address><city>Research Triangle Park</city><state>NC</state><postal>27711</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>000-000-0000</cntvoice><cntemail>EnviroAtlas@epa.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></distrib></distinfo><metainfo><metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv><metd>20220301</metd><metfrd>20210523</metfrd><metc><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>US Environmental Protection Agency, Research Triangle Park</cntorg><cntper>EnviroAtlas Coordinator</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>ORD/NERL/EnviroAtlas</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing address</addrtype><address>109 TW Alexander Dr.</address><city>Research Triangle Park</city><state>NC</state><postal>27711</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>000-000-0000</cntvoice><cntemail>EnviroAtlas@epa.gov</cntemail></cntinfo></metc></metainfo><eainfo><detailed><enttyp><enttypl>USA_Reptile</enttypl><enttypd>Total number of reptile species per 12-digit HUC based on ranges created from USGS GAP</enttypd><enttypds>NMSU</enttypds></enttyp><attr><attrlabl>HUC_12</attrlabl><attrdef>Twelve Digit Hydrologic Unit Code. This field provides a unique 12-digit code for each subwatershed. Numbers were assigned in an upstream to downstream fashion. Where no downstream/upstream relationship could be determined, numbers were assigned in a clockwise fashion.</attrdef><attrdefs>Federal Guidelines, Requirements, and Procedures for the National Watershed Boundary Dataset; Chapter 3 of Section A; Federal Standards, Book 11, Collection and Delineation of Spatial Data; Techniques and Methods 11-A3.</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>010000000000</rdommin><rdommax>999999999999</rdommax></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>SpeciesNumber</attrlabl><attrdef>Number of reptile species identified within 12-digit HUC based on range</attrdef><attrdefs>USGS GAP</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>74</rdommax></rdom></attrdomv></attr></detailed><overview><eadetcit>https://www.epa.gov/enviroatlas/enviroatlas-fact-sheets</eadetcit><eaover>The total species richness for reptiles were estimated using National Gap Analysis range data for each 12-digit HUC in the U.S.  The data used is available at http://gapanalysis.usgs.gov/species/data/download/</eaover></overview></eainfo></metadata>