<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "https://thor-f5.er.usgs.gov/ngtoc/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd">
<metadata>
   <idinfo>
      <citation>
         <citeinfo>
            <origin>U.S. Geological Survey, National Geospatial Technical Operations Center</origin>
            <pubdate>2020</pubdate>
            <title>USGS National Boundary Dataset (NBD) Downloadable Data Collection</title>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
               <pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
               <publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <onlink>https://nationalmap.gov/boundaries.html</onlink>
            <onlink>https://services.nationalmap.gov/bestpractices/model/acrodocs/Poster_BPGovtUnits_03_01_2006.pdf</onlink>
         </citeinfo>
      </citation>
      <descript>
         <abstract>The USGS Governmental Unit Boundaries dataset from The National Map (TNM) represents major civil areas for the Nation,
            including States or Territories, counties (or equivalents), Federal and Native American areas, congressional districts, minor
            civil divisions, incorporated places (such as cities and towns), and unincorporated places. Boundaries data are useful for
            understanding the extent of jurisdictional or administrative areas for a wide range of applications, including mapping or
            managing resources, and responding to natural disasters. Boundaries data also include extents of forest, grassland, park,
            wilderness, wildlife, and other reserve areas useful for recreational activities, such as hiking and backpacking. Boundaries
            data are acquired from a variety of government sources. The data represents the source data with minimal editing or review by
            USGS. Please refer to the feature-level metadata for information on the data source. The National Map boundaries data is
            commonly combined with other data themes, such as elevation, hydrography, structures, and transportation, to produce general
            reference base maps. The National Map viewer allows free downloads of public domain boundaries data in either Esri File
            Geodatabase or Shapefile formats. For additional information on the boundaries data model, go to
            https://nationalmap.gov/boundaries.html. </abstract>
         <purpose>It is a general purpose dataset for users who are not GIS experts. The geospatial data in this dataset are from selected
            National Map data holdings and other government sources.</purpose>
         <supplinf>Features of this dataset are various private and public man-made structures and installations.</supplinf>
      </descript>
      <timeperd>
         <timeinfo>
            <rngdates>
               <begdate>2014</begdate>
               <enddate>present</enddate>
            </rngdates>
         </timeinfo>
         <current>publication date</current>
      </timeperd>
      <status>
         <progress>Complete</progress>
         <update>Irregular</update>
      </status>
      <spdom>
         <bounding>
            <westbc>-179.229655487448</westbc>
            <eastbc>179.856674735386</eastbc>
            <northbc>71.4395725901531</northbc>
            <southbc>-14.4246950942767</southbc>
         </bounding>
      </spdom>
      <keywords>
         <theme>
            <themekt>USGS Metadata Identifier</themekt>
            <themekey>USGS:6dcde538-1684-48a0-a8d6-cb671ca0a43e</themekey>
         </theme>
         <theme>
            <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
            <themekey>boundaries</themekey>
         </theme>
         <theme>
            <themekt>None</themekt>
            <themekey>political and administrative boundaries</themekey>
            <themekey>legal land descriptions</themekey>
            <themekey>land use maps</themekey>
            <themekey>zoning maps</themekey>
            <themekey>cadastral surveys</themekey>
            <themekey>land ownership</themekey>
            <themekey>geographic names</themekey>
            <themekey>boundary</themekey>
            <themekey>Public Land Survey System</themekey>
            <themekey>U.S. National Grid</themekey>
            <themekey>County or Equivalent</themekey>
            <themekey>Incorporated Place</themekey>
            <themekey>Jurisdictional</themekey>
            <themekey>Minor Civil Division</themekey>
            <themekey>Native American Area</themekey>
            <themekey>PLSS First Division</themekey>
            <themekey>PLSS Special Survey</themekey>
            <themekey>PLSS Township</themekey>
            <themekey>Reserve</themekey>
            <themekey>State or Territory</themekey>
            <themekey>Unincorporated Place</themekey>
         </theme>
         <place>
            <placekt>Geographic Names Information System</placekt>
            <placekey>US</placekey>
            <placekey>United States</placekey>
         </place>
      </keywords>
      <accconst>None</accconst>
      <useconst>None. However, users should be aware that temporal changes may have occurred since this data set was collected and that some
         parts of this data may no longer represent actual surface conditions. Users should not use this data for critical applications
         without a full awareness of its limitations. Acknowledgment of the U.S. Geological Survey would be appreciated for products derived
         from these data. </useconst>
      <browse>
         <browsen>https://thor-f5.er.usgs.gov/ngtoc/metadata/waf/collections/boundaries_thumbnail.jpg</browsen>
         <browsed>Thumbnail JPG image</browsed>
         <browset>JPEG</browset>
      </browse>
   </idinfo>
   <dataqual>
      <attracc>
         <attraccr>Cartographic content is derived from USGS national geospatial databases. The data is owned and hosted by the USGS, but
            does not preclude using data sources owned and hosted by other organizations, provided that these sources have been approved by
            the USGS data program.</attraccr>
      </attracc>
      <logic>This product is a layered data datbase. The data is extracted and codified according to USGS standards.</logic>
      <complete>Each layer is extracted from the USGS national geospatial databases.</complete>
      <posacc>
         <horizpa>
            <horizpar>This map product is compiled to meet National Map Accuracy Standards (NMAS). NMAS horizontal accuracy requires that at
               least 90 percent of well-defined points tested are within 0.02 inch of the true position. In this product, the projection
               line, grids, and orthoimage are believed to meet NMAS. Positional accuracy of the other data layers is less controllable
               because of diversity of data sources, and may not meet NMAS.</horizpar>
         </horizpa>
         <vertacc>
            <vertaccr>Vertical accuracy is not applicable to this dataset.</vertaccr>
         </vertacc>
      </posacc>
      <lineage>
         <srcinfo>
            <srccite>
               <citeinfo>
                  <origin>State and Federal Partners</origin>
                  <pubdate>20140401</pubdate>
                  <title>Schools</title>
                  <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
                  <othercit>The schools within this dataset are composed of Public elementary and secondary education in the US as defined
                     and tracked by the National Center for Education Statistics (NCES), Common Core Dataset (CCD). Private schools in this
                     dataset are composed of Private elementary and secondary education in the US as defined by the Private School Survey,
                     NCES. The colleges and Universities are composed of postsecondary education facilities as defined by the Integrated
                     Post Secondary Education System (IPEDS), NCES. Included are Doctoral and Research Universities, Masters Colleges and
                     Universities, Baccalaureate Colleges, Associates Colleges, Theological seminaries, Medical schools and other health
                     care professions, schools of engineering and technology, business and management, art, music, design, Law schools,
                     Teachers colleges, Tribal colleges and other specialized institutions.</othercit>
                  <onlink>https://nationalmap.usgs.gov</onlink>
               </citeinfo>
            </srccite>
            <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
            <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
            <srctime>
               <timeinfo>
                  <rngdates>
                     <begdate>2008</begdate>
                     <enddate>20140218</enddate>
                  </rngdates>
               </timeinfo>
               <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
            </srctime>
            <srccitea>Structures - Schools</srccitea>
            <srccontr>Image</srccontr>
         </srcinfo>
         <srcinfo>
            <srccite>
               <citeinfo>
                  <origin>U.S. Geological Survey, National Geospatial Technical Operations Center</origin>
                  <pubdate>20140401</pubdate>
                  <title>Geographic Names Information System (GNIS)</title>
                  <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
                  <othercit>The Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) is the Federal and national standard for geographic nomenclature.
                     The U.S. Geological Survey developed the GNIS in support of the U.S. Board on Geographic Names as the official
                     repository of domestic geographic names data, the official vehicle for geographic names use by all departments of the
                     Federal Government, and the source for applying geographic names to Federal electronic and printed products.</othercit>
                  <onlink>https://www.usgs.gov/core-science-systems/ngp/board-on-geographic-names</onlink>
               </citeinfo>
            </srccite>
            <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
            <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
            <srctime>
               <timeinfo>
                  <rngdates>
                     <begdate>2012</begdate>
                     <enddate>20140218</enddate>
                  </rngdates>
               </timeinfo>
               <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
            </srctime>
            <srccitea>Geographic Names</srccitea>
            <srccontr>Geographic feature names</srccontr>
         </srcinfo>
         <srcinfo>
            <srccite>
               <citeinfo>
                  <origin>International Boundary Commission</origin>
                  <pubdate>20140401</pubdate>
                  <title>U.S.-Canada National Boundary</title>
                  <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
                  <othercit>The international boundary dataset between Canada and the United States was provided by Maine Office of
                     Geographic Information Systems (MEGIS), University of New Hampshire, Vermont Center for Geographic Information, Inc
                     (VCGI). The dataset was collected from multiple source agencies such as the U.S. Geological Survey, U.S. Department of
                     Commerce, Bureau of Census, Bureau of Parks and Lands, Coastal Island Registry (CIREG) and various state agencies. The
                     data and attribution accuracy was tested by manual comparison of the source with hard copy printouts and/or symbolized
                     display of digital files and corrected by each state GIS department for use at a scale not greater than
                     1:24,000.</othercit>
                  <onlink>http://www.internationalboundarycommission.org/</onlink>
                  <onlink>http://www.internationalboundarycommission.org/products.html#nad83</onlink>
               </citeinfo>
            </srccite>
            <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
            <srctime>
               <timeinfo>
                  <rngdates>
                     <begdate>2006</begdate>
                     <enddate>20140218</enddate>
                  </rngdates>
               </timeinfo>
               <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
            </srctime>
            <srccitea>U.S. / Canada International Boundary</srccitea>
            <srccontr>International Boundary between Canada and the United States</srccontr>
         </srcinfo>
         <srcinfo>
            <srccite>
               <citeinfo>
                  <origin> U.S. Geological Survey, U.S. Department of Agriculture, and the Instituto Nacional de Estadistica y Geografia of
                     Mexico. </origin>
                  <pubdate>20140401</pubdate>
                  <title>U.S.-Mexico National Boundary</title>
                  <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
                  <othercit>The international boundary between Mexico and the United States, defined as a joint venture between the U.S.
                     Department of Agriculture (USDA) and the Instituto Nacional de Estadistica y Geografia of Mexico (INEGI), resulted in
                     an unofficial United States-Mexico boundary dataset that was further enhanced by the U.S. Geological Survey's Border
                     Environmental Health Initiative (BEHI). With the data frame scale set to 1:5,000 in ArcMap, the center of the Rio
                     Grande/Rio Bravo was digitized using the NAIP 2004 Imagery. In areas with dense stands of salt cedar (bounding box = UL
                     -104.714 30.038, UR -104.664 30.037, LR -104.666 29.933, LL -104.717 29.934; NAD83), the center of the channel was
                     difficult, and sometimes impossible, to easily determine. To determine the location of the boundary, the GIS analyst
                     compared the location of the line in the INEGI 1:250K Limited feature class with the NAIP 2004 Imagery and adjusted the
                     boundary to the image, thus, the delineation of the international boundary is less certain in these areas. The
                     remaining part of the border was extracted from the INEGI 1:250K Limited feature class and appended to the line feature
                     class created along the Rio Grande/Rio Bravo. The U.S. Geological Survey reviewed the original USDA data against 2007
                     NAIP imagery and further edited 9 line segments in the Rio Grande areas to conform to National Map Accuracy
                     Standards.</othercit>
               </citeinfo>
            </srccite>
            <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
            <srctime>
               <timeinfo>
                  <rngdates>
                     <begdate>1972</begdate>
                     <enddate>20140218</enddate>
                  </rngdates>
               </timeinfo>
               <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
            </srctime>
            <srccitea>U.S. / Mexico International Boundary</srccitea>
            <srccontr>International Boundary between Mexico and the United States</srccontr>
         </srcinfo>
         <srcinfo>
            <srccite>
               <citeinfo>
                  <origin> U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) Forest Service - Washington Office Automated Lands Program (ALP). </origin>
                  <pubdate>20140401</pubdate>
                  <title>USDA Forest Service Boundary</title>
                  <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
                  <othercit>The forest service boundaries defined by the USDA Forest Service encompassing the National Forest System (NFS)
                     lands within the original proclaimed National Forests, along with lands added to the NFS which have taken on the status
                     of 'reserved from the public domain' under the General Exchange Act. The following area types are included: National
                     Forest, Experimental Area, Experimental Forest, Experimental Range, Land Utilization Project, National Grassland,
                     Purchase Unit, and Special Management Area. The nationwide Proclaimed Forest dataset was created by the USDA Forest
                     Service, Washington Office Automated Lands Program (ALP) staff from collected source data created by the Regional
                     Offices. Only maps in USDA Forest Service areas will contain USDA Forest boundaries.</othercit>
               </citeinfo>
            </srccite>
            <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
            <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
            <srctime>
               <timeinfo>
                  <rngdates>
                     <begdate>2009</begdate>
                     <enddate>20140218</enddate>
                  </rngdates>
               </timeinfo>
               <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
            </srctime>
            <srccitea>USDA Forest Service Boundaries</srccitea>
            <srccontr>National Forest Service Boundaries</srccontr>
         </srcinfo>
         <srcinfo>
            <srccite>
               <citeinfo>
                  <origin>U.S. Census Bureau</origin>
                  <pubdate>20140401</pubdate>
                  <title>State and Equivalent Boundary</title>
                  <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
                  <othercit>The Census Bureau collects boundaries from state and county governments through the Boundary and Annexation
                     Survey (https://www.census.gov/), and publishes the results as TIGER files. The USGS uses
                     the TIGER data without editing or alteration.</othercit>
                  <onlink>https://www.census.gov/data.html</onlink>
                  <onlink>ftp://ftp2.census.gov/geo/tiger/TIGER2010/STATE/2010/</onlink>
               </citeinfo>
            </srccite>
            <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
            <srctime>
               <timeinfo>
                  <rngdates>
                     <begdate>2010</begdate>
                     <enddate>20140218</enddate>
                  </rngdates>
               </timeinfo>
               <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
            </srctime>
            <srccitea>State Boundaries</srccitea>
            <srccontr>State and Equivalent Boundary</srccontr>
         </srcinfo>
         <srcinfo>
            <srccite>
               <citeinfo>
                  <origin>Office of the Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Installations and Environment, Business Enterprise Integration
                     Directorate</origin>
                  <pubdate>20140401</pubdate>
                  <title>U.S. Military Installations, Ranges, and Training Areas</title>
                  <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
                  <othercit>Authoritative locations of Department of Defense sites, commonly referred to as installations, ranges, and
                     training areas. This dataset does not necessarily represent a comprehensive collection of all Department of Defense
                     facilities, and only those in the fifty United States and US Territories were considered for inclusion. Some sites were
                     not included because geospatial data were not available, or because it is a leased site.</othercit>
               </citeinfo>
            </srccite>
            <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
            <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
            <srctime>
               <timeinfo>
                  <rngdates>
                     <begdate>2011</begdate>
                     <enddate>20140218</enddate>
                  </rngdates>
               </timeinfo>
               <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
            </srctime>
            <srccitea>U.S. Department of Defense Military Installations</srccitea>
            <srccontr>Boundary lines, installation names</srccontr>
         </srcinfo>
         <srcinfo>
            <srccite>
               <citeinfo>
                  <origin>U.S. Dept. of Interior, Bureau of Land Management, Division of Support Services, Branch of Information Resource
                     Management</origin>
                  <pubdate>20140401</pubdate>
                  <title>Public Land Survey System</title>
                  <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
                  <othercit>Section boundaries were generated from geodetic latitude and longitude coordinate pairs as recorded on BLM's
                     official protraction diagrams of the state of Alaska. The SDMS_PROD protraction tables were modified to include
                     pro_pt83, section83, and township83. The latitude and longitude values in the pro_pt83 table were transformed from
                     geographic NAD27 coordinates to geographic NAD83 coordinates using NADCON for Alaska. The Informix Section83 table is a
                     spatially-enabled table that contains all of the protraction information for each of the 655,483 sections. Section
                     shapes are stored as NAD83 geographic multipolygons. Each section was individually constructed from NAD83 geographic
                     pro_pt (Protracted Point) table and is fully densified by including all township/section offset corners from adjacent
                     township/sections.</othercit>
                  <onlink>http://sdms.ak.blm.gov/sdms/data_protracted_grid_gis.html</onlink>
               </citeinfo>
            </srccite>
            <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
            <typesrc>digital data</typesrc>
            <srctime>
               <timeinfo>
                  <rngdates>
                     <begdate>2012</begdate>
                     <enddate>20140218</enddate>
                  </rngdates>
               </timeinfo>
               <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
            </srctime>
            <srccitea>Public Land Survey System - BLM</srccitea>
            <srccontr>Townships and ranges, sections</srccontr>
         </srcinfo>
         <srcinfo>
            <srccite>
               <citeinfo>
                  <origin>U.S. Geological Survey, National Geospatial Technical Operations Center</origin>
                  <pubdate>20140401</pubdate>
                  <title>Grids and Coordinate System</title>
                  <othercit>U.S. National Grid, UTM grid, and State Plane Coordinate System values are displayed along the map projection.
                     State Plane Coordinate System State and Zone values are abbreviated per Appendix A in the following document: tem,
                     J.E., 1990, 'State Plane Coordinate System of 1983', NOAA Manual NOS NGS 5, available at
                     http://www.ngs.noaa.gov/PUBS_LIB/ManualNOSNGS5.pdf. </othercit>
               </citeinfo>
            </srccite>
            <typesrc>raster data</typesrc>
            <srctime>
               <timeinfo>
                  <rngdates>
                     <begdate>2012</begdate>
                     <enddate>20140218</enddate>
                  </rngdates>
               </timeinfo>
               <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
            </srctime>
            <srccitea>Grids and Coordinate Systems</srccitea>
            <srccontr>2.5-minute geographic ticks, U.S. National Grid, UTM grid, State Plane Coordinate System ticks.</srccontr>
         </srcinfo>
         <procstep>
            <procdesc>The data for this product are created as follows. All geospatial content is taken from national geospatial databases
               under the stewardship of USGS data programs. The NAIP imagery is provided by a seamless tile service that delivers image data
               at the resolution and quality of the source imagery. The vector data, including grids and collar information, are processed
               using ESRI ArcGIS software and exported. Map formatting is performed using a custom application, which includes
               post-processing to embed the metadata XML document.</procdesc>
            <procdate>20121105</procdate>
         </procstep>
      </lineage>
   </dataqual>
   <spdoinfo>
      <indspref>Public Land Survey System</indspref>
      <direct>Vector</direct>
      <ptvctinf>
         <sdtsterm>
            <sdtstype>Void polygon composed of rings</sdtstype>
            <ptvctcnt>1012</ptvctcnt>
         </sdtsterm>
      </ptvctinf>
   </spdoinfo>
   <spref>
      <horizsys>
         <geograph>
            <latres>0.00001</latres>
            <longres>0.00001</longres>
            <geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
         </geograph>
         <geodetic>
            <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
            <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
            <semiaxis>6378137</semiaxis>
            <denflat>298.2572221</denflat>
         </geodetic>
      </horizsys>
   </spref>
   <eainfo>
      <detailed>
         <enttyp>
            <enttypl>GU_Country</enttypl>
            <enttypd>The geographic area of an independent, self-governing, political entity.</enttypd>
            <enttypds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</enttypds>
         </enttyp>
      </detailed>
      <detailed>
         <enttyp>
            <enttypl>GU_CountyOrEquivalent</enttypl>
            <enttypd>The primary division of a state or state equivalent area. The primary divisions of 48 states are termed County, but
               other terms are used such as Borough in Alaska, Parish in Louisiana, and Municipio in Puerto Rico. This feature includes
               independent cities, which are incorporated places that are not part of any county.</enttypd>
            <enttypds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</enttypds>
         </enttyp>
      </detailed>
      <detailed>
         <enttyp>
            <enttypl>GU_IncorporatedPlace</enttypl>
            <enttypd>A type of governmental unit, incorporated under state law as a city, town (except in New England, New York, and
               Wisconsin), borough (except in Alaska and New York), or village, generally to provide a wide array of specific governmental
               services for a concentration of people within legally prescribed boundaries. New for Census 2000 are "city and borough" and
               "municipality," which serve as both place- and county-level entities in Alaska. A few incorporated places do not have a legal
               description. See consolidated city, governmental unit, independent city, independent place, place.</enttypd>
            <enttypds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</enttypds>
         </enttyp>
      </detailed>
      <detailed>
         <enttyp>
            <enttypl>GU_Jurisdictional</enttypl>
            <enttypd>An administrative unit that defines the scope of a public, private, or nonprofit organization jurisdiction for purposes
               other than use regulation, zoning, or reserve.</enttypd>
            <enttypds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</enttypds>
         </enttyp>
      </detailed>
      <detailed>
         <enttyp>
            <enttypl>GU_MinorCivilDivision</enttypl>
            <enttypd>A type of governmental unit that is the primary legal subdivision of a county or statistically equivalent entity in
               many states and statistically equivalent entities, created to govern or administer an area rather than a specific population.
               MCDs are identified by a variety of terms, such as town, township, or district. The U.S. Census Bureau recognizes MCDs in 28
               states, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and the Island Areas. In 20 states and American Samoa, all or many MCDs are
               active general-purpose governmental units. Many MCDs are not general-purpose governmental units, and therefore do not have
               elected officials to carry out legal functions; instead, they serve as nonfunctioning administrative entities.</enttypd>
            <enttypds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</enttypds>
         </enttyp>
      </detailed>
      <detailed>
         <enttyp>
            <enttypl>GU_NativeAmericanArea</enttypl>
            <enttypd>A U.S. Census Bureau term referring to these entity types: American Indian reservation, American Indian off-reservation
               trust land, tribal subdivision, Oklahoma tribal statistical area, state designated American Indian statistical area, Alaska
               Native Regional Corporation, Alaska Native village, Alaska Native village statistical area, and Hawaiian home land.</enttypd>
            <enttypds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</enttypds>
         </enttyp>
      </detailed>
      <detailed>
         <enttyp>
            <enttypl>GU_PLSSFirstDivision</enttypl>
            <enttypd>First set of divisions for a Public Land Survey System (PLSS) Township, commonly the section, but can also be lots or
               tracts or protracted blocks.</enttypd>
            <enttypds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</enttypds>
         </enttyp>
      </detailed>
      <detailed>
         <enttyp>
            <enttypl>GU_PLSSSpecialSurvey</enttypl>
            <enttypd>This feature class contains the Special Surveys that are nonrectangular components of the Public Land Survey System
               (PLSS) from Bureau of Land Management (BLM) survey records</enttypd>
            <enttypds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</enttypds>
         </enttyp>
      </detailed>
      <detailed>
         <enttyp>
            <enttypl>GU_PLSSTownship</enttypl>
            <enttypd>Public Land Survey System (PLSS) Townships, the primary unit of survey for the PLSS.</enttypd>
            <enttypds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</enttypds>
         </enttyp>
      </detailed>
      <detailed>
         <enttyp>
            <enttypl>GU_Reserve</enttypl>
            <enttypd>Bounded land set aside for a particular purpose, generally having certain use restrictions.</enttypd>
            <enttypds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</enttypds>
         </enttyp>
      </detailed>
      <detailed>
         <enttyp>
            <enttypl>GU_StateOrTerritory</enttypl>
            <enttypd>The geographic area of a primary governmental division of the United States.</enttypd>
            <enttypds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</enttypds>
         </enttyp>
      </detailed>
      <detailed>
         <enttyp>
            <enttypl>GU_UnincorporatedPlace</enttypl>
            <enttypd>A geographic entity that serves as the statistical counterpart of an incorporated place for the purpose of presenting
               census data for an area with a concentration of population, housing, and commercial structures that is identifiable by name,
               but is not within an incorporated place.</enttypd>
            <enttypds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</enttypds>
         </enttyp>
      </detailed>
      <detailed>
         <enttyp>
            <enttypl>GU_BoundaryPoint</enttypl>
            <enttypd>A feature class representing the location of a geographic area or boundary as a single point.</enttypd>
            <enttypds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</enttypds>
         </enttyp>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>Polygon</edomv>
                  <edomvd>2-dimensional element</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>ESRI GIS software</edomvds>
               </edom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Internal feature or event number.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>Auto-generated number assigned by ESRI GIS software</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>Permanent_Identifier</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>A 40-character globally unique ID (GUID) value that uniquely identifies the occurrence of each feature or event in The
               National Map.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>Auto-generated by USGS</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>Source_FeatureID</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Identifier of the feature or event in the source dataset.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>Assigned according to source data organization's procedures</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>Source_DatasetID</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Identifier of the source dataset.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>Assigned according to source data organization's procedures</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>Source_DataDesc</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Brief narrative of the source dataset.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>description of source dataset</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>Source_Originator</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Name of the organization or individual that developed the source dataset.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>Name of the organization or individual that developed the source dataset.</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>Data_Security</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>A code from Executive Order 12958-Classified National Security Information (EO12958) used to describe the highest
               classification of a United States document (e.g., confidential, secret, top secret, no markings).</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>0 = Unknown</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Classification Unknown.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>1= Top Secret</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Information, the unauthorized disclosure of which reasonably could be expected to cause exceptionally grave damage
                     to national security.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>2 = Secret</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Information, the unauthorized disclosure of which reasonably could be expected to cause serious damage to national
                     security.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>3 = Confidential</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Information, the unauthorized disclosure of which reasonably could be expected to cause damage to national
                     security.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>4 = Restricted</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Restricted.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>5 = Unclassified</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Unclassified</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>6 = Sensitive</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Sensitive.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>Distribution_Policy</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Data access and use constraints.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>A1</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Emergency Service Provider - Internal Use Only.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>A2</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Emergency Service Provider - Bitmap Display via Web.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>A3</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Emergency Service Provider - Free Distribution to Third Parties.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>A4</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Emergency Service Provider - Free Distribution to Third Parties via Internet.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>B1</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Government Agencies or Delegated Agents - Internal Use Only.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>B2</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Government Agencies or Delegated Agents - Bitmap Display - Web.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>B3</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Government Agencies or Delegated Agents - Free Distribution to Third Parties.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>B4</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Government Agencies or Delegated Agents - Free Distribution to 3rd Parties via Internet.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>C1</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Other Public or Educational Institutions - Internal Use Only.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>C2</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Other Public or Educational Institutions - Bitmap Display via Web.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>C3</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Other Public or Educational Institutions - Free Distribution to Third Parties.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>C4</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Other Public or Educational Institutions - Free Distribution to 3rd Parties via Internet.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>D1</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Data Contributors - Internal Use Only.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>D2</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Data Contributors - Bitmap Display via Web.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>D3</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Data Contributors - Free Distribution to Third Parties.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>D4</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Data Contributors - Free Distribution to Third Parties via Internet.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>E1</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Public Domain - Internal Use Only.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>E2</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Public Domain - Bitmap Display via Web.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>E3</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Public Domain - Free Distribution to Third Parties.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>E4</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Public Domain - Free Distribution to Third Parties via Internet.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>LoadDate</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Date and time feature or event was loaded into the database. Timestamp indicating when the feature or event was last
               edited.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>timestamp automatically generated during load</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>Name</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Official name of the feature.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>May or maynot be Geographic Names Information System official name.</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>AdminType</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>The type of organization with administrative responsibility for a feature.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>0 = Unknown</edomv>
                  <edomvd>There is no information specified regarding the attribute value.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>1 = Federal</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Federal government entity.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>2 = Tribal</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Tribal entity.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>3 = State</edomv>
                  <edomvd>State government entity.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>4 = Regional</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Regional government entity.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>5 = County</edomv>
                  <edomvd>County government entity.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>6 = Municipal</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Municipal government entity.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>7 = Private</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Individual or a business.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>CensusCode</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>A five-digit numeric place code used to identify legal and statistical entities for county subdivisions, places, and
               American Indian areas/Alaska Native areas/Hawaiian home lands. The Census Code is the same as the former Federal Information
               Processing Standard (FIPS) 55-3 Place Code, which was withdrawn by NIST in 2005 and replaced with the Geographic Names
               Information System feature identifier code (GNIS ID).</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <rdom>
                  <rdommin>00001</rdommin>
                  <rdommax>99999</rdommax>
               </rdom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>IsCapitalCity</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Indicates whether or not the featuret is the capital city.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>0 = Unknown</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Unknown. There is no information specified regarding the attribute value.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>1 = Yes</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Yes, the condition is true for this attribute.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>2 = No</edomv>
                  <edomvd>No, the condition is not true for this attribute.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>IsCountySeat</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Indicates whether or not the boundary point is the county seat.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>0 = Unknown</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Unknown. There is no information specified regarding the attribute value.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>1 = Yes</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Yes, the condition is true for this attribute.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>2 = No</edomv>
                  <edomvd>No, the condition is not true for this attribute.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>GNIS_ID</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>A permanent, unique number assigned by the Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) to a geographic feature name for
               the sole purpose of uniquely identifying that name application as a record in any information system database, dataset, file,
               or document</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <rdom>
                  <rdommin>1</rdommin>
                  <rdommax>9,999,999,999</rdommax>
               </rdom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>GNIS_Name</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>The Geographic Names Information System (GNIS) assigned proper name, specific term, or expression by which a particular
               geographic entity is known.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <codesetd>
                  <codesetn>Principles, Policies, and Procedures: Domestic Geographic Names</codesetn>
                  <codesets>Principles, Policies, and Procedures: Domestic Geographic Names, By Donald J. Orth, Executive Secretary,
                     Domestic Geographic Names (emeritus) and Roger L. Payne, Executive Secretary, United States Board on Geographic Names
                     and Domestic Geographic Names, Third printing (revised) and Preliminary Online Edition, 1997
                     (https://www.usgs.gov/core-science-systems/ngp/board-on-geographic-names).</codesets>
               </codesetd>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>AreaSqKm</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Area of feature in square kilometers. Calculated when feature in Albers Equal Area projection.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>Number representing the area of the feature.</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>Shape_Length</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Length of the feature, which may differ from the field measured length due to differences in calculation. Units are map
               units.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>Number auto-calculated in ESRI GIS</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>Shape_Area</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Area of feature in map units squared.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>Number auto-calculated in ESRI GIS</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>Country_Name</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>The name of the country.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>Name of the country</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>Population</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Population estimate for the feature.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>Number representing the population of the feature.</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>State_FIPSCode</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>A two-digit Federal Information Processing Series (FIPS) numeric code that uniquely identifies States, the District of
               Columbia, Puerto Rico and the Insular Areas of the United States.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <codesetd>
                  <codesetn>Codes for the Identification of the States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and the Insular Areas of the
                     United States.</codesetn>
                  <codesets> INCITS 38:200x, (Formerly FIPS 5-2) Codes for the Identification of the States, the District of Columbia,
                     Puerto Rico, and the Insular Areas of the United States. </codesets>
               </codesetd>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>State_Name</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>The name of the state.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <codesetd>
                  <codesetn>Codes for the Identification of the States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and the Insular Areas of the
                     United States.</codesetn>
                  <codesets>Codeset_Source</codesets>
               </codesetd>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>County_FIPSCode</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>A three-digit Federal Information Processing Series (FIPS) numeric code that uniquely identifies Counties and
               Equivalent Entities of the United States, Its Possessions, and Insular Areas.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <codesetd>
                  <codesetn>Codes for the Identification of Counties and Equivalent Entities of the United States, its Possessions, and
                     Insular Areas.</codesetn>
                  <codesets> INCITS 31:200x, (Formerly FIPS 6-4) Codes for the Identification of Counties and Equivalent Entities of the
                     United States, its Possessions, and Insular Areas. </codesets>
               </codesetd>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>County_Name</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>The name of the county.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <codesetd>
                  <codesetn>Codes for the Identification of Counties and Equivalent Entities of the United States, its Possessions, and
                     Insular Areas.</codesetn>
                  <codesets> INCITS 31:200x, (Formerly FIPS 6-4) Codes for the Identification of Counties and Equivalent Entities of the
                     United States, its Possessions, and Insular Areas. </codesets>
               </codesetd>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>StCo_FIPSCode</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>A five-digit Federal Information Processing Standard (FIPS) numeric code that uniquely identifies counties and
               equivalent entities in the United States, Its possessions, and Associated states. The first two digits are the numeric code
               for a US State and the last three digits are the numeric code for a county within the state or possession.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <codesetd>
                  <codesetn>Codes for the Identification of Counties and Equivalent Entities of the United States, its Possessions, and
                     Insular Areas.</codesetn>
                  <codesets>Codeset_Source</codesets>
               </codesetd>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>Place_FIPSCode</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>A five-digit Federal Information Processing Series (FIPS) numeric code that uniquely identifies populated places,
               primary county divisions, and other locational entities within a state. The codes are assigned based on the alphabetic
               sequence of the entity names within a state. The Place FIPS Code values used in this model are the values reported by US
               Census.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <codesetd>
                  <codesetn>Codes for the Identification of the States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and the Insular Areas of the
                     United States.</codesetn>
                  <codesets>INCITS 38:200x, (Formerly FIPS 5-2) Codes for the Identification of the States, the District of Columbia, Puerto
                     Rico, and the Insular Areas of the United States.</codesets>
               </codesetd>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>Place_Name</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>The name of the place in which the feature is located.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>Name of the place.</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>FRSTDIVID</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>This is a unique identifier for the first division that is built by appending the first division elements on the
               Township identifier.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>Derived from first division elements and township identifier.</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>FRSTDIVNO</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>This is the number, letter or designator for the first division of the PLSS Township.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>Number or character designator for first division</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>FRSTDIVDUP</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>This is a code to indicate whether the first division is a duplicated area or identifier.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <codesetd>
                  <codesetn>unknown BLM domain used to indicate if the first division is a duplicated area or identifier</codesetn>
                  <codesets>Bureau of Land Management (BLM)</codesets>
               </codesetd>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>FRSTDIVTYP</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>This is the type of first division and is commonly the section but may be a lot, parcel, tract or other
               division.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <codesetd>
                  <codesetn>BLM table "LU_PLSSFirstDiv" has a list for the first division types and codes</codesetn>
                  <codesets>Bureau of Land Management (BLM), LU_PLSSFirstDiv table.</codesets>
               </codesetd>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>FRSTDIVTXT</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>This is the first division type as a text field.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>text for BLM first division type</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>PLSSID</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Concatenation of the state, principal meridian, township, range, and duplicate code that forms a unique ID for the PLSS
               Township.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>value derived from the values for state, principal meridian, township, range, and duplicate code</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>FRSTDIVLAB</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>This is the label for the first division that is used for cartographic of web display purposes.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>text used for labeling the first division</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>SURVTYP</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Code for the type of special survey.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <codesetd>
                  <codesetn>BLM table "LU_SurveyType" has a list for the special survey types and codes</codesetn>
                  <codesets> Bureau of Land Management (BLM), LU_SurveyType table. </codesets>
               </codesetd>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>SURVTYPTXT</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Special survey type code text description.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <codesetd>
                  <codesetn>BLM table "LU_SurveyType" has a list for the special survey types and codes</codesetn>
                  <codesets>Bureau of Land Management (BLM), LU_SurveyType table.</codesets>
               </codesetd>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>SURVNO</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>The number of the special survey.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>integer or text represeing the special survey number</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>SURVSUF</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Special survey suffix designation that makes the identification of the area unique.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>text representing the suffix designation of the special survey</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>SURVNOTE</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Notes about the polygon feature that are important for using or understanding the feature.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>A</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Approximate acreage</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Bureau of Land Management, PLSS metadata.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>C</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Conflict or Questionable</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Bureau of Land Management, PLSS metadata.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>D</edomv>
                  <edomvd>No Add Acreage</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Bureau of Land Management, PLSS metadata.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>E</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Exception to survey type coding</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Bureau of Land Management, PLSS metadata.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>M</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Negative Acreage</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Bureau of Land Management, PLSS metadata.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>N</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Not Coded</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Bureau of Land Management, PLSS metadata.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>P</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Records Problem Acreage</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Bureau of Land Management, PLSS metadata.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>R</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Replacement</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Bureau of Land Management, PLSS metadata.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>S</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Salt Water</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Bureau of Land Management, PLSS metadata.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>X</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Exception to standard surveys</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Bureau of Land Management, PLSS metadata.</edomvds>
               </edom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>ACRES</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Area of the feature in acres. The survey note needs to be consulted to determine the type of acres (approximate,
               official etc).</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>number represesnting the area of hte feature.</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>SURVLAB</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Label that is used for cartographic output or web display.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>text for the display label</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>REVISEDDATE</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Survey revision date.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>date representing the last date of any revision in the township</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>STATEABBR</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>State abbreviation code two letter postal code.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <codesetd>
                  <codesetn>USPS two character abbreviation for state name</codesetn>
                  <codesets>US Postal Service. https://www.usps.com/send/official-abbreviations.htm</codesets>
               </codesetd>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>PRINMERCD</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Principal meridian code from the BLM PM Code list.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <codesetd>
                  <codesetn>BLM PM Code list. </codesetn>
                  <codesets>Bureau of Land Management (BLM). LU_PrincipalMeridian table.</codesets>
               </codesetd>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>PRINMER</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Principal meridian name as a text.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <codesetd>
                  <codesetn>BLM PM Code list. </codesetn>
                  <codesets>Bureau of Land Management (BLM). LU_PrincipalMeridian table.</codesets>
               </codesetd>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>TWNSHPNO</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Township number. The Township Number indicates the number of rows of townships, north or south from a Public Land
               Survey System Origin.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>number representing township row, based on PLSS origin</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>TWNSHPFRAC</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Township fraction. Township Fractions are created when there are gaps between surveyed Township boundaries or due to
               excess size in Townships that arose from executing original surveys.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>text representing township fraction</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>TWNSHPDIR</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Township direction. The direction of a row of Townships from a Public Land Survey System Origin. These are typcially
               North and South in the West but may be East and West in Ohio.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>text representing North, South, East or West direction.</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>RANGENO</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Range number. The Range Number indicates the number of columns of townships, east or west from a Public Land Survey
               System Origin.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>text representing the number of columns of townships from a PLSS origin</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>RANGEFRAC</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Range fraction. Range Fractions are created when there are gaps between surveyed Township boundaries or due to excess
               size in Townships that arose from executing original surveys.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>text representing range fraction</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>RANGEDIR</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Range direction. The direction of a column of townships from a Public Land Survey System Origin. These are typcially
               East or West in the west but may be north or south in Ohio.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>text representing North, South, East or West direction.</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>TWNSHPDPCD</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>If there are multiple townships in a Public Land Survey System Origin, State and Survey Name, the Township Duplicate
               Status is used to establish uniqueness. When more than one Public Land Survey System Township has the same Township and Range
               numbers and directions and fractions, and are in the same State, this attribute is used to distinguish among duplicate
               values.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>A</edomv>
                  <edomvd>First Duplicate</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Bureau of Land Management (BLM), 2011. Cadastral PLSS Standardized Data - PLSSIntersected - Version 1.1
                     Metadata.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>B</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Second Duplicate</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Bureau of Land Management (BLM), 2011. Cadastral PLSS Standardized Data - PLSSIntersected - Version 1.1
                     Metadata.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>0</edomv>
                  <edomvd>no duplicate</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Bureau of Land Management (BLM), 2011. Cadastral PLSS Standardized Data - PLSSIntersected - Version 1.1
                     Metadata.</edomvds>
               </edom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>STEWARD</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Data steward for the polygon.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>Text identifying the name of the data steward.</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>TWNSHPLAB</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Township label that is used for cartographic output or web display.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>text used to label the township.</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>SRVNAME</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Survey name.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>text with the name of the survey</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>SECSRVNAME</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>Section survey name.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom>text with the name of the survey</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>NativeAmericanArea_FIPSCode</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>A five-digit Federal Information Processing Series (FIPS) numeric code that uniquely identifies populated places,
               primary county divisions, and other locational entities within a state. The codes are assigned based on the alphabetic
               sequence of the entity names within a state. The FIPS 55 codes are state-based. Native American Areas in more than one state
               will have multiple FIPS 55 codes; that is, a different FIPS 55 code for each state portion of the Native American Area
               entity.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <codesetd>
                  <codesetn>National ANSI Code File for American Indian Areas</codesetn>
                  <codesets>American National Standards Institute (ANSI). American Indian Areas.</codesets>
               </codesetd>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl>OwnerOrManagingAgency</attrlabl>
            <attrdef>The owner or managing agency.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>1 = Army Corps of Engineers</edomv>
                  <edomvd>A federal agency and a major Army command that is the world's largest public engineering, design and construction
                     management agency.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>2 = Bureau of Indian Affairs</edomv>
                  <edomvd>An agency of the federal government of the United States within the US Department of the Interior charged with the
                     administration and management of land held in trust by the United States for Native Americans in the United States,
                     Native American Tribes and Alaska Natives.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>3 = Bureau of Land Management</edomv>
                  <edomvd>An agency within the United States Department of the Interior which administers America's public lands and manages
                     subsurface mineral estate underlying federal, state and private lands.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>4 = Bureau of Reclamation</edomv>
                  <edomvd>An agency under the U.S. Department of the Interior that oversees water resource management, specifically as it
                     applies to the oversight and/or operation of numerous water diversion, delivery, and storage and hydroelectric power
                     generation projects it built throughout the western United States.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>5 = Department of Defense</edomv>
                  <edomvd>The U.S. federal department charged with coordinating and supervising all agencies and functions of the government
                     relating directly to national security and the United States armed forces.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>6 = Department of Energy</edomv>
                  <edomvd>A Cabinet-level department of the United States government concerned with the United States' policies regarding
                     energy and safety in handling nuclear material; its responsibilities include the nation's nuclear weapons program,
                     nuclear reactor production for the United States Navy, energy conservation, energy-related research, radioactive waste
                     disposal, and domestic energy production.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>7 = Department of Homeland Security</edomv>
                  <edomvd>A Cabinet department of the United States federal government with the primary responsibilities of protecting the
                     territory of the U.S. from terrorist attacks and responding to natural disasters.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>8 = Department of Transportation</edomv>
                  <edomvd>A federal Cabinet department of the United States government concerned with transportation.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>9 = Department of Veteran Affairs</edomv>
                  <edomvd>A Cabinet department of the United States government responsible for administering programs of veterans' benefits
                     for veterans, their families, and survivors.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>10 = Fish and Wildlife Service</edomv>
                  <edomvd>A federal government agency within the U.S. Department of the Interior dedicated to the management of fish,
                     wildlife, and habitats.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>11 = Forest Service</edomv>
                  <edomvd>An agency of the United States Department of Agriculture that administers the nation's national forests and
                     national grasslands, which encompass 193 million acres.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>12 = National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</edomv>
                  <edomvd>A scientific agency within the United States Department of Commerce focused on the conditions of the oceans and
                     the atmosphere.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>13 = National Park Service</edomv>
                  <edomvd>A U.S. federal agency that manages all national parks, many national monuments, and other conservation and
                     historical properties with various title designations.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>14 = Tennessee Valley Authority</edomv>
                  <edomvd>A corporation owned by the U.S. government, that provides electricity for people in parts of seven southeastern
                     state sand also provides flood control, navigation and land management for the Tennessee River system and assists
                     utilities and state and local governments with economic development.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>15 = Bureau of Census</edomv>
                  <edomvd>The government agency that is responsible for the United States Census and also gathers other national demographic
                     and economic data.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>99 = Not Applicable</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Not applicable</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>Data Dictionary for Govermental Units. Draft Standards Database, 2013. September 25.</edomvds>
               </edom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
      </detailed>
   </eainfo>
   <distinfo>
      <distrib>
         <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
               <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey, National Geospatial Technical Operations Center</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
               <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
               <address>1400 Independence Road</address>
               <city>Rolla</city>
               <state>MO</state>
               <postal>65401</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntaddr>
               <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
               <address>Box 25046 Denver Federal Center</address>
               <city>Lakewood</city>
               <state>CO</state>
               <postal>80225</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>1-888-275-8747</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>tnm_help@usgs.gov</cntemail>
            <hours>Monday through Friday 8:00 AM to 4:00 PM Eastern Time Zone USA</hours>
            <cntinst>Please visit http://www.usgs.gov/ask/, call 1-888-ASK-USGS or email tnm_help@usgs.gov to contact us.</cntinst>
         </cntinfo>
      </distrib>
      <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
      <distliab>No liability for content or accuracy is presumed by USGS for data.</distliab>
      <stdorder>
         <digform>
            <digtinfo>
               <formname>WAF</formname>
               <formcont>Web Accessible Folder</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
               <onlinopt>
                  <computer>
                     <networka>
                        <networkr>https://thor-f5.er.usgs.gov/ngtoc/metadata/waf/boundaries/nbd/</networkr>
                     </networka>
                  </computer>
               </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
         </digform>
         <fees>None.</fees>
      </stdorder>
      <stdorder>
         <digform>
            <digtinfo>
               <formname>FileGDB</formname>
               <formcont>ESRI File Geodatabase</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
               <onlinopt>
                  <computer>
                     <networka>
                        <networkr>https://prd-tnm.s3.amazonaws.com/index.html?prefix=StagedProducts/GovtUnit/GDB/</networkr>
                     </networka>
                  </computer>
               </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
         </digform>
         <fees>None.</fees>
      </stdorder>
      <stdorder>
         <digform>
            <digtinfo>
               <formname>Shapefile</formname>
               <formcont>ESRI Shapefile</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
               <onlinopt>
                  <computer>
                     <networka>
                        <networkr>https://prd-tnm.s3.amazonaws.com/index.html?prefix=StagedProducts/GovtUnit/Shape/</networkr>
                     </networka>
                  </computer>
               </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
         </digform>
         <fees>None.</fees>
      </stdorder>
      <stdorder>
         <digform>
            <digtinfo>
               <formname>Boundaries Map Server (ArcGIS)</formname>
               <formvern>10.71</formvern>
               <formspec>http://www.geoplatform.gov/spec/esri-map-rest</formspec>
               <formcont>An ArcGIS Map Service for visualizing boundary features.</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
               <onlinopt>
                  <computer>
                     <networka>
                        <networkr>https://carto.nationalmap.gov/arcgis/rest/services/govunits/MapServer</networkr>
                     </networka>
                  </computer>
               </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
         </digform>
         <fees>NONE</fees>
      </stdorder>
      <stdorder>
         <digform>
            <digtinfo>
               <formname>Boundaries Map Server (OGC WMS)</formname>
               <formvern>1.3.0</formvern>
               <formspec>http://opengis.net/spec/wms</formspec>
               <formcont>An OGC WMS Map Service for visualizing boundary features.</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
               <onlinopt>
                  <computer>
                     <networka>
                        <networkr>https://carto.nationalmap.gov/arcgis/services/govunits/MapServer/WMSServer?request=GetCapabilities&amp;service=WMS</networkr>
                     </networka>
                  </computer>
               </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
         </digform>
         <fees>NONE</fees>
      </stdorder>
      <stdorder>
         <digform>
            <digtinfo>
               <formname>Boundaries Feature Server (OGC WFS)</formname>
               <formvern>1.1.0</formvern>
               <formspec>http://opengis.net/spec/wfs</formspec>
               <formcont>An OGC WFS Service for accessing boundary features.</formcont>
            </digtinfo>
            <digtopt>
               <onlinopt>
                  <computer>
                     <networka>
                        <networkr>https://carto.nationalmap.gov/wfs/services/govunits/MapServer/WFSServer?request=GetCapabilities&amp;service=WFS</networkr>
                     </networka>
                  </computer>
               </onlinopt>
            </digtopt>
         </digform>
         <fees>NONE</fees>
      </stdorder>      
   </distinfo>
   <metainfo>
      <metd>20201113</metd>
      <metc>
         <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
               <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey, National Geospatial Technical Operations Center</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
               <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
               <address>1400 Independence Road</address>
               <city>Rolla</city>
               <state>MO</state>
               <postal>65401</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntaddr>
               <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
               <address>Box 25046 Denver Federal Center</address>
               <city>Lakewood</city>
               <state>CO</state>
               <postal>80225</postal>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>1-888-275-8747</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>tnm_help@usgs.gov</cntemail>
            <hours>Monday through Friday 8:00 AM to 4:00 PM Eastern Time Zone USA</hours>
            <cntinst>Please visit http://www.usgs.gov/ask/, call 1-888-ASK-USGS or email tnm_help@usgs.gov to contact us.</cntinst>
         </cntinfo>
      </metc>
      <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
      <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
   </metainfo>
</metadata>
